<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>CAAMASI</Key>
  <Name>Caamasi</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Caamasi[h4]
    The Caamasi are a sentient mammalian species of furred humanoids
    known for their compassionate and peace-loving nature; indeed, the
    name Caamasi came to mean "friend from afar" and "stranger to be
    trusted" in some languages across the galaxy.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    A species of furry mammalians, the Caamasi are covered in dense
    grey or brown fur and have a spicy, woody body scent that is similar
    to that of Corellian whiskey. They have two, long arms with thin,
    three-fingered hands, and two pointed ears which stick out from
    the sides of their heads. They also have an extremely acute sense
    of smell, with their nose positioned at the end of a tooth-filled snout.
    [P]Caamasi have the interesting ability to share vivid memories called
    memnii with their near relatives and Force-sensitives, especially
    members of the Jedi Order. A memnis is as vivid to one who receives
    it as it is to the one who participated in the event remembered. Their
    peace-loving natures are accounted for in part due to memnii, as
    having a memory of killing or harming would be particularly strong.
    In time, it would become unbearable, and something Caamasi would seek to
    avoid except in defense of themselves or others.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
    A pacifist race, culture on Caamasi evolved around the basic tenants
    of peace and social justice. Working as explorers,
    diplomats and artists, the Caamasi are a monogamous people who value
    single partners while mating and starting a family. So culturally ingrained
    was this notion that there are great debate among the species following
    the devastation of their homeworld. The Caamasi who are offworld at the
    time considered evolving to a position of polygamy so as to regrow the
    population. While the argument was one of survival, many sociologist
    familiar with the culture of the Caamasi believed that they would not
    accept the idea. The famed celebration known as the Rainbow of
    Sunshine Festival is held on Caamas annually and beloved by the populace.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Caamas was a highly populated and marsh-covered Core World in the Cirius
    system, the second planet orbiting the star Cirius. It is notable for
    the devastation it suffered during an Imperial orbital bombardment which
    destroyed its ecosystem and nearly wiped out the native Caamasi.
    [P]Caamas was once a temperate, hospitable world of jungles, marshes, steppes,
    and rolling hills. Its dense rainforests and jungles teemed with life.
    After the Imperial bombardment, nearly all flora and fauna either disappeared
    or were mutated beyond recognition. Caamas became a barren waste, and without
    vegetation to release oxygen, the atmosphere became toxic and unbreathable.
    The bombardment kicked up smoke and dust into the air, and the surface became
    wracked by dust storms and falling soot, eroding the surface and sending dirt
    and mud into the oceans. The waters, once teeming with sea life, became muddy,
    polluted, stagnant, and lifeless.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    Caamasi was the official language of Caamas and is still spoken by the native Caamasi 
    in addition to Galactic Basic Standard. After the devastation of the planet, 
    the surviving Caamasi were able to keep the language alive through the continued 
    use and sharing of memnis from generation to generation.
  </Description>
  <Source Page="19">Desperate Allies</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>1</Cunning>
    <Willpower>3</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>11</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>CAAABSK</Key>
      <Name>Skills</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>CAASKCH</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Charm</Name>
          <Description>Caamasi may begin the game with one rank in Charm.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>CHARM</Key>
              <RankAdd>1</RankAdd>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
        <Option>
          <Key>CAASKDEC</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Discipline</Name>
          <Description>Caamasi may begin the game with one rank in Discipline.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>DISC</Key>
              <RankAdd>1</RankAdd>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice> 
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>CAAAB2</Key>
      <Name>Memories</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>CAAAB2CLAW</Key>
          <Name>Memnii</Name>
          <Description>
            Once per game session, a Caamasi may form a new memnis that encompasses one scene or encounter.  At any time, a Caamasi may perfectly recall any memnis that he has formed or witnessed, or share it with another Caamasi or Force-sensitive.
          </Description>
          <DieModifiers>
          </DieModifiers>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
