<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>CATHAR</Key>
  <Name>Cathar</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Cathar[h4]
    The Cathar are a species of feline, bipedal humanoids native to Cathar,
    a planet of savannas and rough uplands. They are known for their loyalty,
    passion, and temper. Quick and powerful, they are considered great warriors
    and dedicated, efficient predators. Cathar have high moral values, learned
    from both family and society. Their females are prized as slaves, whereas
    the males are generally regarded as too uncontrollable for slavery.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    The baseline Cathar has fur-covered bodies with thick manes. They have
    prominent, retractable claws that can deliver powerful killing attacks
    on foes and prey. Their bodies also possess rapid healing abilities. On
    average, Cathar are 1.5 to 1.9 meters tall. These traits make them the
    perfect hand-to-hand specialists.
    [P]The Cathar species also had two additional subspecies, known as the
    Juhani and the Myr Rho. Both of these are notably less catlike than
    mainline Cathar. Cathar are born into a litter.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
    On their homeworld, Cathar live in cities built into giant trees, and are
    organized into clans governed by "Elders." Stories of their great heroes are
    often carved into the trunks of these tree-homes for following generations to
    see. The Cathar mate for life, to the extent that when one mate dies, the
    survivor never has a relationship with another. Cathar clan society includes
    great pageants and celebrations, especially for their heroes. Their religion
    includes a ritual known as the "Blood Hunt," in which Cathar warriors individually
    engage in combat against entire nests of Kiltik in order to gain honor and purge
    themselves of inner darkness.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Cathar is the homeworld of the Cathar species, filled with many ecological niches 
    and huge insect predators. The natives live in city-trees, while wide areas of the 
    planet are made barren by kiltik beetles. The Giant horned hopper are often killed 
    by the Cathar species in blood hunts.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    The native language of the Cathar was Catharese,
    which included the emphasis of some spoken words with a growl.
  </Description>
  <Source>Unofficial Species Menagerie</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>3</Agility>
    <Intellect>1</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <WeaponModifiers>
    <WeaponModifier>
      <AllSkillKey>BRAWL</AllSkillKey>
      <DamageAdd>1</DamageAdd>
      <Crit>3</Crit>
    </WeaponModifier>
  </WeaponModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>CATHABSK</Key>
      <Name>Skills</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>CATHSKCH</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Athletics</Name>
          <Description>Cathar may begin the game with one rank in Athletics.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>ATHL</Key>
              <RankAdd>1</RankAdd>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
        <Option>
          <Key>CATHSKDEC</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Stealth</Name>
          <Description>Cathar may begin the game with one rank in Stealth.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>STEAL</Key>
              <RankAdd>1</RankAdd>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>CATHAB1</Key>
      <Name>Claws</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>CATHAB1CLAW</Key>
          <Name>May use claws when brawling</Name>
          <Description>
            When a Cathar makes a
            Brawl check to deal damage to an opponent,
            their attack deals +1 point of damage and has
            a Crit Rating of 3.
          </Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
