<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>CEREAN</Key>
  <Name>Cerean</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Cerean[h4]
    Cereans are a sophisticated and cultured humanoid mammalian species hailing from
    the planet Cerea in the Mid Rim. They have tall tapering heads, which house large
    binary brains, enabling them to focus on many things at the same time. Aside from
    this unique feature, Cereans are physically similar to Humans, although they each
    possesse two hearts, which supply extra blood circulation to support their brains.
    [P]Cerean males age more quickly than the females, who have similar lifespans to
    Humans. Thus, there are fewer males than females. Polygamous marriage are a
    necessity in order for the species to survive. Each male usually has one primary
    "bond-wife", and between four and ten "honor-wives".
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    The Cereans' enlarged skulls, extending up to twenty centimeters above their
    foreheads, house complex binary brains, provided with sufficient blood by an
    extra heart in their heads. The binary structure of Cerean thinking helps
    them to ponder two sides of an issue at once. It also enables them to process
    information and solve problems rapidly and provides a highly advanced capacity
    for concentration and meditation. Because of their thoughtful nature, they tend
    to be calm, rational and analytical, preferring peaceful philosophies and a
    lifestyle which works in harmony with nature. Though the quick-thinking Cereans
    have equally quick reflexes, they are commonly not as well coordinated as Humans.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
    Cereans developed a low–tech society on their homeworld and prefer to live
    in isolation from the wider galaxy. During the years leading up to the Invasion
    of Naboo, a generational dispute erupted on Cerea when the younger generation
    took up a rebellious stance against their low–tech society. Many Cerean youths
    wished to own such technology as was commonplace in the Galactic Republic, like
    starships and speeder bikes.
    [P]Many Cereans use specially-forged Kasha crystals as a meditational tool. By
    focusing one's thoughts while in contact with such crystals, distractions are
    eliminated, creating an exceptional meditation environment.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Cerea is a planet located in the Mid Rim region of the galaxy. The homeworld
    of the Cerean species, Cerea is notable for its inhabitants' harmonious relationship
    with nature. Technology and pollution are frowned upon by the conservative
    government, a major point in the planet's decision not to join the Galactic Republic.
    The Cerean population mainly live in giant buildings that take up a minimum of
    space, allowing the remainder of the planet's area to be employed as farmland.
    Foreign immigrants and visitors are, with a few exceptions, only allowed in Cerea's
    Outsider Citadels, enormous buildings erected to let non-Cereans practice their
    technological ways. This ensures that the foreigners' technology does not contaminate
    Cerea's nature, but also leads to a concentration of criminal elements within the Citadels.
    [P]Cerea is ruled by the Council of Elders, which in turn is led by a president.
    The planet was for the most part ignored by the Republic until a few years prior to
    the Clone Wars. Cerea's seclusion caused a unique culture to develop, one that focused
    on other values than the mainstream galactic civilization. In 21 BBY, Cerea was the
    site of a battle between the Republic and Confederacy of Independent Systems, which
    had an adverse effect on the planet's relatively untouched nature.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    Cerean is the official language of the planet Cerea.
    It is mainly spoken by native Cereans. Despite their isolationist stance, 
    the Cereans also learn to speak Basic as children.
    [P]"Chu'unthor" is the Cerean word for "academy," and the word "Barsen'thor" translates 
    to "Warden of the Order."
  </Description>
  <Source Page="54">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>1</Agility>
    <Intellect>3</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>13</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>90</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>VIGIL</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
    </SkillModifier>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key></Key>
      <RankStart>0</RankStart>
      <RankAdd>0</RankAdd>
      <RankLimit>0</RankLimit>
      <isCareer>true</isCareer>
      <SkillType>Knowledge</SkillType>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
