<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>CHISS</Key>
  <Name>Chiss</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Chiss[h4]
    The Chiss are a tall, blue-skinned Near-Human civilization from the planet
    Csilla in the Unknown Regions, best known to most Humans as the people to which
    Grand Admiral Thrawn belonged. Due to the remote position of their home
    territory in the Chiss Ascendancy they remain largely an enigma to the
    rest of the galaxy, and contact with outsiders was limited even in the days of
    the Galactic Alliance.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    The Chiss are a near-Human species distinguished by their blue skin and glowing
    red eyes, which grow darker depending on the oxygen content of their surroundings.
    The more oxygen present, the more intense the color of their eyes and skin tone.
    While their hair is typically jet black, it does on rare occasions go gray with
    age (most Chiss believed that the development of gray hair is an indication of
    the siring of exceptional children). Their physical form leads to some speculation
    on whether they are an offshoot of humanity's ancient expansions into the galaxy
    or whether their physical form coincidentally matched that of Humans. However,
    genetic analysis indicates that they are an offshoot of humanity, and it is believed
    that moving underground led to a divergence between them and baseline Humans.
    Furthermore, this analysis indicates that their unique skin tone is the result of
    exposure to glacial minerals. Their blue skin, jet black hair and red eyes
    generally command attention once they are in a crowd of regular humanoids, and
    these features make them physically striking and instantly recognizable. Male
    and female Chiss tend to be more powerfully built when compared to Humans but exhibit
    the same variances as Humanoid sexes. A Chiss stands between either 1.6 to 2.1 meters
    in height though an average height of an adult is 1.7 meters.
    [P]The University of Sanbra concluded that the fact that all Chiss often appear in
    very good physical shape is an indication that the species possesses an active metabolism
    which is responsible for their trim figure. Thus, this is believed to be responsible
    for preventing obesity that was commonly found within more sedentary humanoids. While
    the report concluded that they were indeed near-Humans, they had not determined a
    specific point of evolutionary divergence. There was, in fact, a Human sleeper
    ship colony established on Csilla around 27,500 BBY, though records of this were
    virtually nonexistent and it remained unknown how a remote area of the galaxy could
    have been trailblazed so far back. They did display, physiologically, very few
    signs of evolutionary adaptations to their icy environment with even their skin
    pigmentation not providing any apparent benefit. Beyond the obvious physical features,
    physiologically, the Chiss are similar to Humans to the point that they possess a
    comparable circulatory, neurological, digestive and reproductive systems. The Chiss
    vocal mechanism is noted for being similar to Humans but there are apparent differences
    which are evident in their capacity to speak their native language.
    [P]In addition, they experience a greatly accelerated growth rate compared to Humans,
    which contributes to their reaching maturity faster than Humans. Thus a Chiss at the age
    of 10-years holds the physical maturity of a 20-year old Human. This in turn results in
    a culturally-imprinted emotional maturity that is many times above that of their Human
    counterparts. They are capable of living up to 80 years old, at which point a Chiss
    is considered venerable; children are between ages 1-10, and they experience a rapid
    adolescence from 11-12 and are considered full adults by 13-14. Middle-age follows
    between the ages of 51-62, and those aged 63-79 are considered old.

    [P][B]Society:[b]
    Galactic perceptions of Chiss behavior is, following the Battle of Endor, much based
    on the personality of Grand Admiral Thrawn. However, following that period, it became apparent
    that Thrawn himself was an exceptional member of his kind with all Chiss demonstrating
    individually different traits. The impression held by the galaxy was that the Chiss were arrogant,
    aloof and calculating beings. However, while this is true in some cases, the Chiss demonstrate
    varying personality types similar to other species. General traits demonstrated by them, however,
    are being well-educated, artistic and cautious when dealing with outsiders. Outsiders have the general
    impression that the Chiss are very polite and highly civilized species. Their reputation means
    that they are both respected and, in some cases, feared.
    [P]The harsh cold conditions of Csilla led to the Chiss developing a self-reliant streak which is
    the core of their notoriously aloof personalities. This leads to outsiders characterizing their
    race being as cold as the ice plains of their homeworld. As a people, they are intelligent
    as well as highly valuing of their privacy. This extreme protection of their society is what
    allowed them to remain hidden from the rest of the galaxy for so long. They are described as
    being pensive as well as contemplative, deliberate and calculating. This means that they often
    study situations from many different viewpoints. As such, they consider all alternatives to
    a situation and even consider scenarios of what would have happened if they had made different
    decisions. In combat situations, Chiss act both calmly and intelligently as well as form
    well planned strategies. Chiss do not give themselves over to passion and instead view
    problems as curiosities that need to be solved through rigorous application of brainpower.
    As such, they do not allow hot emotions to interfere with their methodical analysis of a problem
    through logic. In terms of personality, they often display a cold, arrogant and disciplined
    behavior. Though they show a cold lack of emotion, their actions are not necessarily
    impartial as most are motivated by the pursuit of power which is encouraged by their ruling families.
    [P]In general, they live a harsh but disciplined life style where self control along with propriety
    are the most valued character traits that all Chiss aspire to. While passions themselves are
    recognized, they are done so with disdain as such energy is believed to be better applied elsewhere.
    The regimented style of their society means that crime is abhorred and seen as the weakness of
    an individual. Blaming society is a notion completely alien to their mindset and justice is given
    with little thought on compassion. However, the Chiss do not believe in capital punishment as
    they recognize it as being an irrational, emotionally driven reaction instead of being a true
    deterrent. Instead, the greatest punishment they give for their most heinous of crime is exile.
    Due to the great importance of family loyalty existing in their culture, exile is considered a
    grave punishment for any Chiss to face.
    [P]During their childhood, Chiss are taught to read through the great stacks of data of the great
    library on Csilla. These contain basic information that every Chiss absorbs during their childhood
    after years of intense schooling. Among their kind, there are no period of adolescence as their
    children mature early and are given adult responsibilities very quickly. Scientists believe
    that they essentially bypass the adolescent stage and reach maturity quickly. By the age of
    ten, they are ready to join military service and wear cadet uniforms.
    [P]The species is highly
    reserved in their emotions and often do not display feelings openly; either by smiling or by warm
    gestures. As such, they rarely are vocal about any feelings of anger or frustration though
    they do possess some curse words to employ should the situation warrant such an expression.
    [P]Though this is the impression projected, the Chiss are also a thoughtful people. While they
    are deliberate and calculating, they are not above wondering about how certain events might have
    turned differently had circumstances been altered. Much of their ability to solve problems stem from
    their reliance on data, and when faced with unpredictable situations, typical Chiss behavior means that
    they would rather flee the scene. This is not a universal characteristic as certain individuals with
    the ability to learn under such circumstances, like Thrawn, are able to continue to fight.In fact,
    whenever a Chiss suffers a setback or even a defeat, they often contemplate what might had been done
    differently in order to ensure that a victory is achieved in the next engagement.
    [P]Chiss are noted
    for possessing an unparalleled aptitude for tactical thinking. The ideals of the Chiss are idolized
    in the form of the Red Flame which is a combination of courage, discipline and cunning.
    Their society is highly structured and ordered with the rule of law being enforced by the ruling
    families. These are not biological family groupings but instead different branches of their government.
    The Csapla dictates colonial issues, natural resources and agriculture whilst the Nuruoda handle
    the military as well as foreign affairs. Inrokini are responsible for industry, science, communication
    and non-military technology with the Sabosen taking the duty of overseeing justice, public health as well
    as education. These ruling families are composed of clans that are headed by government officials
    known as Aristocras. Those chiss that belong to the same house defend one another at every opportunity
    whilst those from competing houses search for facts that could be used to snipe or undermine the other
    whilst attempting to secure any advantage for themselves. Though Thrawn was an exceptional member of his
    species, his rational approach to problem solving was shared by the ruling families that govern the
    Chiss Ascendancy. Members of the ruling class of Chiss are notable for being an aristocracy within
    their society.
    [P]As a general rule, Chiss do not take part in any action that would bring shame on their house with
    entire family lines exiled due to the actions of a single member. The ruling families themselves are
    quite aware of any opportunity where they are able to exploit the weakness of a rival. As such, they are
    quick to take offense at any insult that is perceived against their position. Those Chiss caught in the
    middle of inter-house rivalries spend much of their time in intelligence gathering in order to get useful
    information that could be used for blackmail even if it was only capable of being used many years in the
    future. This trait makes the Chiss excellent counterintelligence agents with a trained member of their kind
    able to see through disguises, evaluate body language, detect idiosyncrasies in speech pattern and even
    distinguish authentic items from forgeries.
    [P]The long spacefaring history of the Chiss led to the creation of a superior combat force with their
    starfighter pilots being infamous throughout the Unknown Regions. Such squadrons are ruled by discipline
    and their pilots are known to spare disabled starships if they broadcast a surrender. They also do
    not celebrate until their duty is completed as any celebrations made before such an event are considered
    false. Despite this, they are highly committed in their duties and a Chiss warrior, if given an order,
    will carry it out even if they disagreed with it, which highlights their belief in the chain of command.
    It is also known that the Chiss as a culture has an aversion to suicide and expendability as they find
    those actions to be wasteful. Though this is the case, there were occasions where Chiss gave their
    lives rather then surrender. In such circumstances, this is either due to the importance of the strategy
    for their people or because surrendering to a certain foe is considered a fate worse than death.
    [P]The Chiss have a keen interest in art and science and are skilled in mathematics. Their thought
    processes are based around a logical mindset, being interested in philosophy and in learning about other
    cultures. On the other hand, they are also xenophobic, and any knowledge gained from other cultures is
    used as a means of gaining a advantage over a potential foe.
    [P]Their clinical detachment is similar to how a biologist studied an insect which is how the Chiss view
    their foes and they often engage in extreme caution in such circumstances. When among non-Chiss, individual
    members of the race are often aloof and pensive as they plot tactics which would ensure a victory if a
    confrontation were to occur. Chiss never truly lose their xenophobic instincts, even when they are among
    members of other species for long periods of time. Ultimately, Chiss are loyal to their own kind and
    looked down upon aliens as being barbaric as well as immature. Despite this fact, most Chiss are
    considered peaceful and abide by the strict code of conduct that governs their race. In addition,
    though xenophobic, they are at times willing to accept members of other races into their ranks so long
    as they prove to be exceptional as well as trustworthy individuals. Furthermore, the subject needs
    to prove themselves capable of following Chiss disciplines in order to gain their loyalty and respect.
    The Chiss are considered an honorable people who do not kill more than they think is necessary to
    accomplish their goals. However, they are not above using biological weapons of mass destruction
    against a foe should it be felt that their survival is being threatened.
    [P]When attacked, they respond with calm, intelligent and well-planned strategies while at the same time
    remaining an honorable species. They never make conflicts personal and are very rarely aggressors as
    they prefer to let conflicts come to them. Among the most famous traits of their kind is their refusal
    to invade the territories of other species or even wage war over potential foes. As such, they do not
    believe in the concept of a preemptive strike against their foes. Rather, they only respond to an enemy
    assault after their foes have struck first. This is actually a by-product of their cool and cautious
    philosophy. This is because, in their view, that by allowing their enemy to draw first blood they guarantee
    that that they are acting in the right. Furthermore, it divorces their actions from any recklessness which
    results from either impulsive anger or the incomplete intelligence of an enemy's intentions. Striking
    first is thus an anathema to their discipline with even tactically sound preemptive strikes being the
    subject of controversy. This moral imperative is so pervasive in their culture that they exiled Thrawn
    from their society for breaching it. Once attacked, the Chiss do not rest until their attackers are
    destroyed or completely subjugated.
    [P]The Chiss society has no concept of finances or money with everything being provided for by the state.
    They also maintain tightly controlled borders that are self-sufficient in the isolated territory that
    they rule. Their colonies supply them with both food and resources while developing technology comparable
    to the rest of the galaxy. As such, they see no need for trade and their culturally derived contempt of
    "lesser races" also prohibits them from forming better relations with their neighbors. In fact, the motive
    for their exploration and expansion is difficult to determine as they lack the passion for conquering
    the unknown which is a trait that Humans possessed. In addition, they do not claim new territory out of
    greed or for a hunger for power. Their space program is mostly governed by the basic need to manage their
    population and gathering resources without upsetting their homeworlds ecosystem. Their territory suffices
    for their entire population needs. A report by the University of Sanbra indicates that the Chiss population
    numbered nearly 5 trillion. Despite their growing border, they still foster a cultural contempt for other
    species. Instead, they believe in isolation and the preservation of their heritage.
    [P]It is believed by many xenosociologists that the rigid and disciplined nature of Chiss society stemmed
    from their cold environment on their homeworld. They are noted for displaying no signs of decadent or greedy
    behavior and thus it is concluded that any signs of colonial expansion are mostly due to the Chiss desiring
    to put order onto chaotic locations. This is in fact the leading theory by the University of Sanbra who
    concluded that the motivation for Chiss expansion was their ideal of seeking to impose order on what they saw
    as a chaotic and barbaric region. Being nearly impossible to enrage, they prefer to only act when all
    factors have been taken into account with the issue itself analyzed. In addition, they believe firmly in
    the chain of command as well as positions of authority. In fact, Chiss are taught to respect the position
    itself rather then the person holding that title. As such, Chiss often respond when an individual calls
    out the rank rather then their name.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Csilla, the homeworld of the Chiss, is a cold world of glaciers and snowy wastes located deep within
    Chiss Space, and serves as the capital of the Chiss Ascendancy.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    The Chiss language is Cheunh and was first accepted during the developing years of their civilization 
    when they formed a planet-wide government which consisted of a single tongue that their society accepted. 
    It is known to be a dense and difficult synthetic language to master as complicated ideas are expressed 
    by uniting unrelated words into larger words. Thus, it has relatively few core words though the syntax 
    requires the speaker to piece together compound words which are complex and involved. One factor that 
    certainly adds to the complexity of the language is the fact that written Cheunh is not set down in a 
    phonetic alphabet. In writing, Cheunh do not possess an abstract alphabet like Aurebesh with ideograms 
    representing concepts and complex ideas being expressed by combining simpler ideograms. The Chiss hold 
    great pride in not only understanding but conversing in such a convoluted language. It is hard for 
    outsiders to understand though Car'das believed it to be logical, and the Chiss believe that the 
    grammar is logical and easy to learn. However, the Chiss believe it is quite impossible for non-Chiss 
    to learn to speak it properly. Though this complex nuance-filled language is difficult for non-Chiss 
    to master due to its intracacies, the Chiss themselves have little trouble mastering Basic though many 
    are unfamiliar with it. At least some phrases in the language are highly idiomatic – the pejorative 
    "moactan teel" literally meant "fair-haired", implying that something about the addressee was non-Chiss, 
    and thus barbarous.
  </Description>
  <Source Page="20">Enter the Unknown</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>3</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>1</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>COOL</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>CHABSK</Key>
      <Name>Sight</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>CHSKCH</Key>
          <Name>Infravision</Name>
          <Description>Chiss have adapted to be able to see in both the infrared and normal visual spectra.
          This enables Chiss characters to remove up to [SETBACK] added to checks by lighting conditions.</Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
