<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>CLAWDITE</Key>
  <Name>Clawdite</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Clawdite[h4]
    Clawdites are a humanoid sentient species native to the planet of Zolan.
    They are one of the few shape-shifting species in the galaxy, and are sometimes
    referred to as Changelings.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    In their natural form, Clawdites have the appearance of reptilian humanoids, and in fact have
    evolved from reptomammals. They have sunken cheeks with a narrow nose and a small mouth.
    A thin line runs down their foreheads and creases the center of their noses. They possess
    large eyes with slit-like pupils, and their irises can be yellow, gold, or blue.
    Their skin is considered to be rough, and ranges in color from green to yellow. Overall,
    their appearance is identical to that of their genetic forebears, the Zolanders.
    [P]Due to genetic manipulation, Clawdites possess the extremely rare ability to change
    their appearance. When using this ability, they can change the color and texture of their
    skin and eyes, mimicking the appearance of other similarly-shaped beings, such as Humans.
    Shifting into a Weequay, a species with similar facial features, is considered to be an
    easy task. Though they can not add physical mass to their bodies, they are able to
    form hair, and can actually make it quite long. Clawdites are also able to mimic the
    appearance of clothing or jewelry, provided that the item lays directly on their skin, as
    it is merely a manipulation of their skin's texture. They can not change the appearance
    of their actual clothing, and have to rely on holographic technology in order to change such items.
    [P]The growth of their abilities mainly relies upon a Clawdite's age. Younglings are only
    able to change color, a talent that begins at infancy, and baby Clawdites use different hues
    and colors to indicate their needs to their parents.

    [P]Unlike most shape-changing species, the Clawdite's shifting abilities actually cause them
    great physical discomfort. While the range of their abilities vary in individuals, with
    both age and practice, they can work through the pain of changing in order to alter their
    appearance in more and more extreme ways. Even the most talented Clawdite, however,
    lacks the fine coordination it would take to mimic a specific individual's appearance precisely.
    Only a very talented Clawdite is able to sleep and retain their altered form. If a Clawdite
    is suitably distracted or hurt, and certainly if they are killed, they will revert to their
    true form.

    [P]It is thought to be impossible for a Clawdite to actually change their body structure or
    body mass, though it appears that some individual Clawdites managed this feat through unknown
    means. As most sentient beings' bodies
    are composed mostly of water, xenobiologists speculated that the Clawdites ability to change
    may lie in the manipulation of water.

    [P][B]Society:[b]
    By nature, Clawdites are quiet and solitary beings, often shunning the company of others
    unless it benefited them. They view the rest of the galaxy pragmatically, and are
    often harsh realists who are  mistrustful and suspicious of others.
    [P]Not all Clawdites use their shape-shifting abilities, but those who do are forced to
    undertake great physical pain and effort in order to do so. They often learn meditation
    and concentration techniques, over long periods of time, in order to maximize their capabilities.
    It is also necessary for Clawdites to treat their skin with specialized oils in order to prevent
    cracking or tearing, due to the difficulty in physically maintaining their disguises.
    [P]While in their natural form, they are considered to be indistinguishable from their Zolander
    brethren, but it is possible to distinguish the two via genetic examination.

    [P]On their homeworld of Zolan, Clawdites are feared and shunned by the Zolanders, who are a deeply
    religious people. Among their many strong convictions, the Zolanders believe the Clawdites to be impure
    and sinful. Because of their prejudice, the Zolanders forced the Clawdites to live in slums all
    across the planet. These ghettos are secured, so that the Zolanders could prevent the Clawdites from
    spreading. This subjugation continued for centuries on end, and it wasn't until after 4 ABY that they
    were able to change their situation. After the rise of their new government, the Clawdites began
    to hold classes for schoolchildren, in order to teach them greater control and efficiency with their
    abilities.

    [P]The few Clawdites who leave their world most often took advantage of their natural abilities to
    join militaristic professions, such as spying, assassination, and bounty hunting. Joining groups
    such as these are the rare occasions where Clawdites afford their loyalty to others, and they
    see it as a positive contribution to the galaxy. They often seek to protect the liberties of
    other species, sensing in their pain the disparity their own people suffered.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Zolan was the homeworld of the Zolander species and its Clawdite offshoot. The Zolanders were
    loyal to the Galactic Republic, but the Clawdites were loyal to the Confederacy of Independent
    Systems, with the false hope the Confederacy would liberate them from Zolander oppression.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    Clawdite is the language of Clawdites, from planet Zolan. It is a modified version of Zolanese.
    Spoken Clawdite is basically formed by hissing sibilants. Guttural croaks are used in some 
    parts of the sentence.
  </Description>
  <Source>Unofficial Species Menagerie</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>90</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>DECEP</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
    <TalentModifier>
      <Key>INDIS</Key>
      <RankAdd>1</RankAdd>
    </TalentModifier>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>CLAAB1</Key>
      <Name>Changeling</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>CLAAB1CON</Key>
          <Name>Change Form</Name>
          <Description>
            At the cost of 2 Strain, a
            Clawdite can choose to upgrade their Deception
            check to convey a false appearance which lasts
            until the Clawdite wills the change to end, or
            until they are knocked unconscious or killed. The
            Strain spent is not recovered until the Clawdite
            reverts back to their normal shape.
          </Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
