<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>DEVAR</Key>
  <Name>Devaronian</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Devaronian[h4]
    Devaronians are a horned humanoid species from the world of Devaron in the Colonies,
    a planet of low mountains and deep valleys linked by thousands of rivers. It is
    believed that they are descended from a race of primates that lived in the mountains
    of Devaron, and that their horns were a genetic mutation that proved useful in fending
    off predatory birds.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    The Devaronians are one of the more unusual races in the galaxy, with a dramatic gender
    dimorphism in appearance and temperament. The males are aggressive by nature, many being
    described as brash or bull-headed, with typically red-tinted skin and a pair of large
    horns growing from their heads. They take great pride in their horns, and groom them
    quite regularly.  Many species feel uncomfortable in their presence, for they resembled the devils of
    a thousand different myths.

    [P]Female Devaronians are covered in thick fur that range in color from brown to white,
    hornless and have prominent canine teeth. They are docile, non-aggressive creatures.
    They tend to be dominant in their culture, being the only ones allowed to participate
    in government and politics. Several female Devaronians not covered with thick fur reveal
    two dark circles above the forehead, where the horns usually are in males.

    [P]In addition, the teeth of the males are all sharp incisors, but the females also have molars
    and prominent canines. One in fifty Devaronian males have two sets of teeth, however, having an
    inner set of sharp "male" teeth and an outer, retractable set of "female" teeth. In primitive times,
    such males were used as solitary scouts by Devaronian tribes, since they could survive on either
    meat or plants. Males also have an extremely long tongue, though whether females shared this trait
    is unknown. The teeth are useful for some languages. A Devaronian has to continually and repeatedly
    retract and extend both sets of teeth to speak Huttese, causing aches over time.

    [P]Their bodies are denser than most humanoids' and as a result they are heavier than their
    appearance would tend to indicate. Perhaps as a result, they have multiple livers. Their blood is
    silver based.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
    Devaronians have a strong matriarchal culture. The female plays the dominant part in the upbringing
    of the young and even the only part in local, planetary and inter-planetary politics. Males are considered
    to be too disruptive to homelife because of their whimsical nature, so the fact that they leave to wander
    the stars is generaly welcomed by their wives. It does not mean males do not care for their offspring
    though; they do all they can to support their families back home by sending them as much credits as
    they can earn. On the rare occasions they re-visit their homeworld it's a time for all-out celebration
    and much 'disruption' for the family as the males will do their best to have fun times with their
    relatives. Eating, drinking, giving presents and playing games are some of the key events during those
    times. Anthropologists have found habits like these to exist within many more cultures galaxy-wide,
    often on an annual basis.
    [P]There is also a darker side to Devaronian society: Crime is punished hard and the worst capital offenses
    are sentenced with the death penalty. Many other species have laws that condemn someone to death but the
    way one is executed on Devaron is galaxy-wide considered to be the most cruel of all. The accused and
    convicted criminal will be led into a small ceremonial arena. Then a pack of Quarra, a savage predatory
    species native to Devaron, is set loose to rip him or her apart. The expression Look to the skies is the
    last thing the criminal will hear before this gruesome death. By doing so the victim exposes the throat
    and other soft tissue inviting the Quarra to make the kill fast and, hopefully, less painful. These words
    also found their way into everyday Devaronian language. 'Looking to the skies' has become synonymous for
    resigning oneself to a certain fate or decission that can't be influenced anymore.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Devaron is the home world of the Devaronians. It is located in the Colonies, near the Corellian Trade
    Spine. It is a planet of low mountains and deep valleys linked by thousands of rivers. The planet has
    strict capital punishment and a matriarchal government.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    Devaronese is the native language of Devaronians, and the official language of their planet, Devaron.
    It is a guttural language using many consonants similar to grunts and grumbles.

    [P]Most of its native speakers are bilingual in Devaronese and Basic; however, they usually spoke 
    Basic with a remarkable accent due to the influence of Devaronese. Strangely, male Devaronians 
    usually do not read Basic, while female Devaronians can read and write Basic.
  </Description>
  <Source Page="100">Nexus of Power</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>3</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>1</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>11</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>95</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>DEVABSK</Key>
      <Name>Skills</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>DEVSKDEC</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Deception</Name>
          <Description>Devaronian may begin the game with one rank in Deception.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>DECEP</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
        <Option>
          <Key>DEVSKSW</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Survival</Name>
          <Description>Devaronian may begin the game with one rank in Survival.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>SURV</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>DEVAB2</Key>
      <Name>Physiology</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>DEFAB2OP1</Key>
          <Name>Resillient Metabolism</Name>
          <Description>
            Devaronians add automatic [SU] to all Resillience checks.
          </Description>
          <DieModifiers>
            <DieModifier>
              <SkillKey>RESIL</SkillKey>
              <SuccessCount>1</SuccessCount>
            </DieModifier>
          </DieModifiers>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
