<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Species xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>DRESSELLIAN</Key>
  <Name>Dressellian</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Dressellian[h4]
For most of their history, they lived a peaceful and isolated lifestyle on their homeworld, Dressel, until the Galactic Civil War forced them into closer contact with the rest of the galaxy as supporters of the Alliance to Restore the Republic, and later, the New Republic.
[P][B]Physiology:[b]
Dressellians are a tall, thin, humanoid species with elongated, hairless skulls, wrinkled skin, and teal-colored blood who value freedom above anything else.  Because of the masses of wrinkles on their faces, "outlanders" often referr to them as "prune-faces," a moniker which Dresselians consider derogatory and highly offensive.
[P][B]Society:[b]
Dresselians are generally fiercely independent, highly valuing personal freedom. Due to this fact, their government is a loose coalition that is determined periodically by popular vote. Their independence also plays a fairly significant role in their interactions with the rest of the galaxy, as they tend to be isolationists and usually opt out of the larger galactic meetings unless specifically encouraged by their Bothan neighbors to attend.
[P][B]Homeworld:[b]
The only planet in the Dressel system, Dressel is one of the more idyllic planets in the galaxy. Its lush forests and jungles give the planet a soothing feel and keep the air temperature at quite a pleasant level all year round. The grasslands and deserts allow a wide variety of fauna and flora to flourish, including the planet's only indigenous, sentient species, the Dresselians.
[P]The planet was originally discovered by the Bothan Askarr clan around two hundred years ago, who decided to leave the Dresselians alone. With many small settlements, the Dresselians were never taken seriously by the rest of the galaxy as they were believed to be a primitive, undeveloped race. Only the Jedi scouts who came to the planet centuries ago saw the great potential in the Dresselians and the Dresselians bestowed great honour upon them. They followed the Jedi into larger galactic affairs and the Dresselians that were later trained to be Jedi were known for their proficiency with the Force.
[P][B]Language:[b]
The Dresselian language, Dresselese, has been described by galactic linguists as being somewhat primitive. Due to the fact that they have had a considerable amount of interaction with the Bothans, who initially discovered the Dresselians around 200 years before the Galactic Civil War began, Dresselians speak using many borrowed words from Bothese. Most of the borrowed words are for items which are considered more technologically advanced than those the Dresselians had created themselves.</Description>
  <Source Page="22">Stay on Target</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>3</Willpower>
    <Presence>1</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>11</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <DefenseRanged>0</DefenseRanged>
    <DefenseMelee>0</DefenseMelee>
    <SoakValue>0</SoakValue>
    <Experience>110</Experience>
    <ForceRating>0</ForceRating>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>SURV</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers />
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>DRESSELLIANCH1</Key>
      <Name>Technology</Name>
      <Description />
      <Source />
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>DRESSELLIANCH1OP1</Key>
          <Name>Primitive</Name>
          <Description>Dressellians must upgrade the difficulty of any checks involving non-Dressellian technology.</Description>
        </Option>
        <Option>
          <Key>DRESSELLIANCH1OP2</Key>
          <Name>Non-Primitive</Name>
          <Description>Tech-saavy Dressellians do not need to upgrade the difficulty of checks involving non-Dressellian technology.</Description>
          <StartingAttributes>
            <Experience>-10</Experience>
          </StartingAttributes>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
  <WeaponModifiers />
</Species>