<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>DUG</Key>
  <Name>Dug</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Dug[h4]
    Dugs are an aggressive mammalian species native to the planet Malastare that used
    their upper limbs for locomotion and their lower limbs for grappling.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    The Dugs have leathery skin which is smooth and some of it hangs loosely around their tall necks only to
    inflate during the mating season calls. They also possess fin-like ears, a pronounced snout and small
    beady eyes. They can easily walk on their hind legs, their forelegs, or all fours. They used their four
    hands to help them move through the trees of their homeworld of Malastare. Much of their language
    is punctuated with knuckle rapping and foot stomping. They are also slender, powerfully built beings
    with a somewhat humanoid build and a unique method of walking that hailed from the high gravity
    world Malastare. Their primary means of locomotion were their strong arms, and their lower limbs
    and feet were used for grappling and other fine motor manipulation. They hardly ever walked on their
    lower limbs. Although most Dugs may walk on all four limbs, others liked to use their strong arms as
    legs and their feet as hands like they would normally do.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
    Dug society is insular and they turn into self-congratulatory braggarts. Well-known for being a disreputable
    lot and could often be found in dingy cantinas or dark alleys with all four arms into something illegal.
    However with a casual glance at their culture on Malastare you could be forgiven for thinking such stories
    were mere rumours. The arboreal Dugs lived in primitive villages in the trees called "tree thorps" and were
    seemingly in touch with nature, though their culture was actually filled with violence.
    [P]Due to their oppression under their Gran rulers who colonized Malastare many Dugs often felt the need
    to throw around their strength in bids to establish dominance. As a result they were known for their
    ill-tempered demeanour and many were known to be bullying thugs.
    [P]On their homeworld of Malastare the vast majority of Dugs were little more than laborers toiling for
    the enrichment of the Gran. With the species excluded from much of the power and money on Malastare many
    Dugs turned to podracing as their only means to achieve fame and fortune. In all other areas the Dugs
    were exploited and disenfranchised. Some even obtained transport off their homeworld to seek means of
    making their fortunes in less Gran dominated regions of the galaxy.
    [P]When it comes to mating season Dug mating is very reminiscent of some reptiles which may indicate
    their ancestry. The loose folds of skin around the males neck will inflate during the mating season
    showing a display of color. An interested female may pester or disturb a male in a few different ways
    until his balloon-neck deflates with a screech. After this the two are considered mated. Mates remain
    loyal to each other even though they may bully each other through their time together.
    [P]Because of their experiences with the Gran the Dugs are xenophobic. If they are seen off-planet they
    are often seen in groups of their own kind. Most Dugs in the galaxy are reportedly criminals or
    risk-takers which lead many Dugs into podracing and gambling.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    [P]The planet of Malastare is located within the Malastare System, Dustig Sector in the south of the galaxy.
    It's sister planet is Lacca and the two planets are the only planets within the Dustig Sector. The sector
    is surrounded largely by unpopulated sectors except for the Quess Sector. The system of Malastare is
    located within the south-west of the Dustig Sector.
    [P]Malastare is a large planet full of a variety of different types of terrain allowing for a large diversity
    of life to be sustained on the homeworld.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    Dug was the native language of the Dug species from the planet Malastare.
    [P]As Dugs are a subservient species to the Grans, Dug language is not as widely used as Dugs would 
    like to be since the Gran language is usually preferred.
    [P]Although many Dugs are forced to learn Gran, most of them decide not to learn Basic, hoping to 
    force others to learn Dug language, thus acknowledging their society.
  </Description>
  <Source Page="22">Special Modifications</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>3</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>1</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>9</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>8</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>90</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>BRAWL</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
    <TalentModifier>
      <Key>DEFDRI</Key>
      <RankAdd>1</RankAdd>
    </TalentModifier>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
