<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Species xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>DUROS</Key>
  <Name>Duros</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Duros[h4]
    The Duros are a humanoid species native to the planet Duro who were among
    the galaxy's first space faring civilizations.
    [P]Their homeworld is located on both the Corellian Trade Spine and at the end of the Duros Space Run,
    two major hyperspace routes that link Duro with other important commercial centers.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    Duros are a humanoid race characterized by their blue skin, red eyes and long, thin faces. There is no
    nose on their face. They have lipless mouths and green blood. Olfactory glands beneath their eyes
    are responsible for their sense of smell. Both females and males are bald, though both genders are
    easily distinguished. Their large red goggle-like eyes also have slit pupils. Duros females give birth
    to live young, and like the Neimoidians they are born in a larval grub stage, but unlike their cousins
    who left the raising of their young mainly to the state, the Duros take care of their offspring from
    birth.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
    While usually taciturn, Duros enjoy telling stories about their travels. It is said Duros have a
    photographic memory when it came to the telling of tales and stories. Many Duros are pilots and
    explorers, and are adventurous, though sometimes rash. As one of the first cultures to develop
    a hyperdrive spacecraft (some even believe the first), Duros-charted trade routes are among the
    oldest hyperspace routes still in use during the Imperial era. Duros are  known for their superior
    astro-navigational skills. Their affinity for
    traveling leads many Duros to prefer the honorific title of "Traveler" despite their occupation or
    craft of choice, and addressing them as such is considered good etiquette.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    [P]Their home planet Duro is primarily uninhabited due to massive pollution on the world over time.
    Instead, it is covered with automated farms for food production. The Duros live in twenty orbital
    space cities above the planet.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    The Duros language is Durese, which is a [I]lingua franca[i] of sorts amongst spacers.
  </Description>
  <Sources>
    <Source Page="55">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Source Page="21">Enter the Unknown</Source>
  </Sources>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>1</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>3</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>11</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>PILOTSP</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankAdd>0</RankAdd>
      <RankLimit>0</RankLimit>
      <isCareer>false</isCareer>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers />
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>DUROSCH1</Key>
      <Name>Navigator</Name>
      <Description />
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>DUROSCH1OP1</Key>
          <Name>Intuitive Navigation</Name>
          <Description>Add [ADVANTAGE] to all Astrogation checks.</Description>
          <DieModifiers>
            <DieModifier>
              <SkillKey>ASTRO</SkillKey>
              <AdvantageCount>1</AdvantageCount>
            </DieModifier>
          </DieModifiers>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
  <WeaponModifiers />
  <NoForceAbilities>false</NoForceAbilities>
</Species>