<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>EWOK</Key>
  <Name>Ewok</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Ewok[h4]
    Ewoks are sentient diminutive furry bipeds native to the forest moon of Endor. They are curious individuals
    that stand about one meter tall; they are omnivorous and
    use spears, slings, and knives as weapons; they also use hang gliders, battle wagons, and bordoks
    as vehicles. Although extremely skilled in forest survival and the construction of primitive technology
    like gliders and catapults, the Ewoks have yet to progress past stone-level technology when discovered
    by the Empire. They were quick learners, however, when exposed to advanced technology with simple
    mechanical processes and concepts.
    [P]Some Ewoks have been removed from their planet and taken as pets or slaves. Others left voluntarily out
    of a sense of curiosity, especially after the Battle of Endor led to the establishment of New Republic
    trading posts on the Forest Moon.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    Ewoks are sentient humanoid mammals, averaging about one meter in height, which can provide an
    advantage when trying to hide. They are covered in fur from head to toe, with brown and black
    the most common colors. Other Ewoks have near-white or reddish fur, but red fur is supposedly
    the rarest shade an Ewok can get. Most Ewoks have solid-colored fur, though a few sported stripes.
    Ewoks have large, bright eyes, small humanoid noses, and hands that possessed two fingers and an opposable
    thumb. Despite their small size, Ewoks are physically strong enough to overpower combat-trained Humans.

    [P][B]Society:[b]
    The tribal structure of the Ewoks have a Council of Elders ruling over each village, headed by a chief. A medicine
    man also lives in the Ewok village, a keeper of mystical lore, and a healer to the injured. The warriors of the
    different tribes wear raggedy garments on the head to signify the Ewok's tribe. The warriors also wear wooden
    chest shields, the jawbones of tiny animals, and sharp teeth. Some decorate themselves with ornaments such
    as feathers, necklaces, and pendants, making their body look like a clutter of trinkets.
    [P]Prominent members of Ewok tribes carry totems to symbolize their rank. The lead warrior wears a headdress
    made of feathers called the "white wings of hope". The eldest son of the tribal leader's family wears a headdress
    called the "red wings of courage". The second son wears the "blue wings of strength".
    [P]The Ewoks enjoy singing and playing music during celebrations, festivals, and rituals. Ewoks also believe
    that music enhances their work. Ewoks are resourceful and tended to make use of everything they can get
    their hands on, so they use a variety of drums, horns, flutes, and other simple instruments in their music.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Endor, also known as Tana among the Ewok species was the cyan gas giant planet orbited by the forest moon of
    Endor. The name "Endor" was also sometimes used for the forest moon. The planet itself was less well known
    than the moon.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    Ewokese is the language spoken by the Ewoks. Ewoks are able to learn and speak other languages, including Basic.
    Ewokese is related to other tongues on the Forest Moon of Endor. Many linguists suggest that the language 
    developed from the Yuzzum language, which was taught off-world, and which suggests a possible relationship 
    between the Ewoks and Yuzzums. Most Ewoks understand Yuzzum and have no difficulty 
    communicating with Duloks, suggesting that the Dulok language may be a dialect of Ewokese.
  </Description>
  <Source>Unofficial Species Menagerie</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>1</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>3</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>9</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>EWABSK</Key>
      <Name>Skills</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>EWSKST</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Stealth</Name>
          <Description>Ewoks may begin the game with one rank in Stealth.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>STEAL</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
        <Option>
          <Key>EWSKSUR</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Survival</Name>
          <Description>Ewoks may begin the game with one rank in Survival.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>SURV</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>EWAB1</Key>
      <Name>Scent</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>EWAB1COO</Key>
          <Name>Heightened Smell</Name>
          <Description>
            Ewoks may remove all [SETBACK]
            imposed due to concealment against a target
            that is within Short Range.
          </Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>EWAB2</Key>
      <Name>Size</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>EWAB2PER</Key>
          <Name>Reduced Silouette</Name>
          <Description>
            Ewoks have a Silhouette of 0.
          </Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
