<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>FALLEEN</Key>
  <Name>Falleen</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Falleen[h4]
    The Falleen are the indigenous reptilian sentient species of the planet Falleen.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    The Falleen are an exotic, cold-blooded reptomammalian species known to be
    long lived, with life spans averaging 250 years.
    [P]The sleek symmetry of their features, calculating and cold demeanors, their
    exotic looks, and their ability to alter their skin pigmentation means that
    the Falleen are often considered to be among the most aesthetically pleasing
    beings in the galaxy. In addition to their strikingly beautiful appearance,
    the Falleen exude pheromones which made them all but irresistible to both
    sexes. They have small scales all over their bodies, as well
    as slightly clawed fingers and toes. In addition, the Falleen display
    prominent facial and spinal ridges, though females tend to have slighter,
    more subtle growths.
    [P]The Falleen are semi-aquatic, and are able to hold their breath underwater
    for a long period of time, leading exobiologists to believe that the Falleen's
    ancestors were completely aquatic. The appearance of breasts and other mammalian
    characteristics in Falleen females and males have also led exobiologists to
    believe that Falleen had a mammal ancestor.
    [P]They are one of the few species resistant to mind tricks, and had green blood.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
    Falleen society is of a feudal nature, with noble houses ruling over the lower
    classes. The upper echelons of Falleen monarchies are rife with politics and intrigue,
    but they rarely spill blood over blatant disputes or open warfare. The skin
    pigmentation of the Falleen change naturally to reflect the mood of the individual;
    however, the Falleen long ago mastered the ability to change their skin tone at
    will and use this as something of a covert weapon in their politics, fostering
    an appearance of calm, for example, when they are really panicking.
    [P]As a cold-blooded species, the Falleen respect discipline and control,
    particularly self-control. They tend to shun public displays of emotion, and are
    very patient. As a result of this attitude, they tend to look down on the more
    openly passionate, whom they see as lacking self-control. Indeed, the Falleen as a
    species have a towering sense of superiority which they felt is only right and proper
    due to their discipline and rigid self-control. They also tend to view Falleen,
    and not Coruscant, as the civilized and cultural capital of the galaxy. This arrogance
    make the Falleen something of an isolationist species, and though they are not a rare
    species, it is rare to find them away from their homeworld.
    [P]Young Falleen nobles often tour the galaxy for a while to acquire a taste of
    life away from Falleen. More often than not, though, this merely reinforces the
    Falleen's biased views and sense of superiority, ensuring that the youth of Falleen
    never feel the desire to leave home.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Falleen is a planet in the Mid Rim region and home to the Falleen species. It
    has jungles, vast plains, and icy mountains.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    Falleen is the native language of the Falleen species from the planet Falleen.
    [P]Falleens leaving their home planet learn to speak Basic as well.
  </Description>
  <Source Page="18">Fly Casual</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>1</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>3</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>12</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>90</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>CHARM</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankAdd>0</RankAdd>
      <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
      <isCareer>false</isCareer>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>FALLEENOC1</Key>
      <Name>Ability</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>FALLEENOC1OP1</Key>
          <Name>Beguiling Pheromones</Name>
          <Description>Once per check as an incidental, may suffer 2 strain to upgrade ability of Charm, Deception, 
          or Negotiation check against living, sentient being within short range.  No effect if wearing breath mask 
          or having no respiratory system.</Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
