<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>FARGHUL</Key>
  <Name>Farghul</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Farghul[h4]
    The Farghul were felinoid sapients indigenous to Farrfin. They had claws, incredible strength and speed, and were covered with tawny fur and possessed prehensile tails.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    Farghul have feline characteristics, as well as prehensile tails.  They average in
    height between 1.7 and 2.0 meters and have light brown to dark brown skin and
    fur.  They are long-lived, averaging 215 standard years.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
    The species has a reputation for being both fearsome fighters as well as cunning
    thieves. The
    Farghul are also generally distrustful of politicians and are considered slightly
    xenophobic. Despite this, they are known to friends as mischievous and playful
    beings who love telling bad jokes. Many Farghul are also known to rig games.
    Their reputation for being cheaters, con artists, and thieves originates from
    this; though, upon being caught, those Farghul will often return their illicit
    winnings. Farghul are extremely self-conscious about their appearance, and
    often wear elaborate clothes or jewelry.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Farrfin is the capital of Farrfin sector and the Farghul homeworld. It has three major
    cities: Farlhu, Jahhnu and Geltyu. A strong criminal
    element thrives in these cities, with con-artists running sabacc scams on every
    street corner, and pockets being picked often. The famed Jahhnu betting houses
    take in incredible sums of currency, as gullible off-worlders and bored smugglers
    gamble away their earnings.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    Farghul is the native language of the Farghul species from Farrfin.
    Most Farghuls also learn to speak Basic, which has hindered the 
    expansion of the Gotal language.
  </Description>
  <Source>Unofficial Species Menagerie</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>1</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>3</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
    <TalentModifier>
      <Key>CONV</Key>
      <RankAdd>1</RankAdd>
    </TalentModifier>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>FARAB1</Key>
      <Name>Skills</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>FARAB1OP1</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Deception</Name>
          <Description>Farghul may begin the game with one rank in Deception.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>DECEP</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
        <Option>
          <Key>FARAB1OP2</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Skulduggery</Name>
          <Description>Farghul may begin the game with one rank in Skulduggery.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>SKUL</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
