<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>GAMORREAN</Key>
  <Name>Gamorrean</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Gamorrean[h4]
    Gamorreans are porcine humanoids from the lush jungle Outer Rim planet of Gamorr
    where their technological level is equivalent to lower technology periods that
    Human civilizations experienced more than 25,000 years before the battle of
    Yavin. They also colonized the planet Pzob in the K749 system and were the
    majority sentient species on Lanthrym in the Elrood sector. Their vessels
    provide only essential amenities as well as shields and weapons. Gamorreans
    are typically green-skinned with a large powerful physique, and are known
    to be fierce warriors prized for their great strength and brutality in combat.
    They are organized into clans headed by a Council of Matrons. In Gamorrean
    society female sows perform all the productive work while the male boars
    concentrate on training for and fighting wars. They speak Gamorrese (also
    called Gamorrean). One of their favorite weapons is a traditional war axe
    called an arg'garok that is forged specifically for beings of extraordinary
    strength and a low center of gravity.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    Gamorrean males average about 1.8 meters in height and can weigh more than
    100 kilograms. They have thick snouts, close set eyes, tusks and two small horns
    on their heads. Their average body temperature is 40.56 °C (105 °F) and their
    verbal tones range from 50 to 13,000 hertz.
    [P]Although a typical Gamorrean is squat, green and heavily built not all
    share these characteristics. Most Gamorreans have a dark greenish coloration
    over a large portion of their bodies; however skin coloration does vary,
    particularly among females, with light skinned and two-toned pigmentation
    not uncommon. Black, brown, pinkish yellow, and even a rare white pigmentation
    are possible. Boars tend to have less skin variation and have a greater
    tendency towards dark green skin perhaps because of their higher exposure
    to the radiation of the Gamorr Star. Eye coloration varies evenly between
    gold-yellow, blue, black and brown. The Gamorreans generally put no importance
    on skin or eye coloration although there are some superstitions linked to
    certain markings.
    [P]Not all Gamorreans are heavy and squat. Although this is the most common
    and generally the desirable appearance in Gamorrean society some individuals
    are comparatively lean and tall.
    [P]They are largely viewed as mindless, intellectually inferior brutes by
    the wider galactic community. This perception may be partly due to
    their physiology, which makes it nearly impossible for them to speak Galactic
    Basic. Their vocal apparatus make it impossible for them to speak clearly
    in any language other than their native language.
    [P]Gamorreans are typically covered by a number of parasitic bloodsuckers
    native to Gamorr called morrts. They show great affection for the creatures
    and consider them adorable pets. The number of morrts that a Gamorrean
    hosts is related to their status within a clan. A clan Warlord or Matron
    could have up to 20 of these parasites feeding on them.
    [P]The Gamorrean diet mainly consists of fungus that grows plentifully on their
    homeworld. A species of mobile mushrooms called Snoruuk are one of the most widely
    eaten varieties along with Fug. They drink an alcoholic beverage called Potwa beer.
    [P]Newly born Gamorreans are called "feeders" until they are weaned. Once
    weaned the younglings are called "shoats" until the age of 3 when they began
    gender specific training. Gamorrean childhood ends after about 6 years from
    which point they are considered young adults. When they reach the age of
    13 they are considered mature adults and the boars will go to war. Biologically
    they are capable of living beyond the age of 45 but the violent nature of their
    existence means that very few boars reached that age.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
    Gamorreans are organized into clans ruled by a male warlord and his wife, a head
    sow who is the most powerful of the clan matrons. While the warlord and his boars
    are solely concerned with preparing and participating in battle with rival clans,
    the matrons of the clan perform all the productive work including farming, hunting,
    manufacturing weapons and running businesses.
    [P]Females within a clan are all related to each other and can trace their lineage
    back to a common matriarch. Boars, however, are exchanged between clans at an early
    age and some will change their allegiance during their adult lives. Clans range
    in size from a few dozen to over a hundred but typically a clan constitutes about
    20 sows, fifty boars and the young. The young are mostly born in the spring
    ("slushtime") and the litters typically range between three and nine. The male to
    female ratio is about ten-to-one with females only being born about every second
    litter. Despite this, a high fatality rate among boars, due to their violent lives,
    result in a predominance of older females.
    [P]Clans own and control areas of land and are always interested in acquiring
    more. Land is gained by either colonizing unclaimed areas or more commonly taking
    land from rival clans. Since the amount of available arable land on Gamorr is scarce
    several clans often lay claim to the same piece of land, and they spend their time
    fighting over possession. A female typically has up to a dozen husbands during their
    lifetime since a boar's lifespan is limited by his violent lifestyle.
    [P]Sows do all the useful work within Gamorrean society and they own and lease
    all property. They are capable of being as rough as the males and they actively
    encourage boars to engage in bloody act of violence to demonstrate their virility.
    Daughters inherit their mother's land evenly and therefore over generations these
    holdings diminish in size. A matron consolidating land is a critical reason for
    the ongoing wars between clans.
    [P]Clan matrons are a select group of sows with the greatest of land who constituted
    the clan council of matrons. They usually have a number of clan Tusker boars in
    admiration of their beauty and status. A matron can often be distinguished from
    a lesser clan sow by the presence of a small number of bodyguards and the relatively
    large number of morrts that they host. The council of matrons is led by a head sow
    who is the richest and most powerful of the clan matrons.
    [P]Sows are responsible for all trading with non-Gamorreans. They are typically
    interested in obtaining weapons and food supplies with long lives. They will pay
    for such goods with gold or other precious metals if they have any or by boar mercenary
    contract.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Gamorr is the agrarian homeworld of the pig-faced Gamorreans, located in the
    Opoku system of the Outer Rim.
    [P]Its varied terrain ranges from frozen tundra to deep forests, and is considered
    quite pleasant by off-worlders. Nevertheless, tourism is highly discouraged to
    Gamorr because of the vicious lifestyle of ferocious, bloody warfare constantly
    being waged between rival Gamorrean clans.
    [P]Prominent mushrooms are also found on Gamorr, as are native coolsap trees.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    Gamorrese, or Gamorrean language is the native language of the Gamorrean species 
    from planet Gamorr and colonies like Pzob.
    [P]Gamorrese is just a bunch of lexicon, mainly nouns and verbs plus a few 
    adjectives, with a primitive syntax. Although apparently there are no declensions 
    in Gamorrean, it is unclear if the word order provides the meaning of the sentences.
    [P]Gamorreans use Gamorrean words as their names, so that the meaning of a 
    Gamorrean name is, more or less, some kind of threat. Other Gamorreans can 
    be intimidated if they hear "I am Ortugg", or "I'm going to Ortugg you".
    [P]Although Gamorrese does not have a sophisticated written language it does have 
    a very basic runic alphabet which is used for record keeping, accounting and 
    genealogy. The runic alphabet is only typically used by educated sows although a 
    fair number of boars can read them slowly. There are known to be several 
    variations of the runic alphabet. Since Gamorreans encountered in the galaxy are 
    mostly males it is generally considered that the Gamorreans have no written language.
  </Description>
  <Source>Unofficial Species Menagerie</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>3</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>1</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>12</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>8</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>90</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>MELEE</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <WeaponModifiers>
    <WeaponModifier>
      <AllSkillKey>BRAWL</AllSkillKey>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>VICIOUS</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
    </WeaponModifier>
    <WeaponModifier>
      <AllSkillKey>MELEE</AllSkillKey>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>VICIOUS</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
    </WeaponModifier>
  </WeaponModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>GAMAB1</Key>
      <Name>Combat</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>GAMAB1OP1</Key>
          <Name>Savage Warrior</Name>
          <Description>
            When making a Brawl or Melee check, Gamorreans add
            the Vicious 1 quality to their weapons.  If the weapon
            already has the Vicious quality, increase the listed
            value by one.
          </Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
