<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>GOTAL</Key>
  <Name>Gotal</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Gotal[h4]
    Gotals are a species of tall, hairy humanoid sentients native to the moon Antar 4.
    Their most distinctive features are the twin conical horns growing on the top of
    their heads, which acted as highly responsive electromagnetic sensors. These head
    cones are sensitive enough to pick up subtle changes in another being's
    electromagnetic emissions from emotional changes, making Gotals natural empaths.
    The unique nature of these sensors shape Gotal culture, and help individual
    Gotals carve niches in galactic society ranging from bounty hunters to diplomats.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    Gotals possess cranial horns as receptors to sense electromagnetism and other
    energy emissions. These nerve-ending filled cones can sense the natural
    electromagnetic fields produced by Antar, Prindaar, and Antar 4's magnetite-rich
    crust, allowing the species to operate even in total darkness. Their senses
    also pick up the electromagnetic auras from other life forms. Gotal hunters can
    sense their quarry from up to ten kilometers away, and can track herds of quivry
    for weeks. While hunting, a Gotal can determine the amount, species type, and
    level of sickness of animals by relying on their cones alone. When close to their
    target, they can ascertain information on its mood, awareness, and state of mind.
    As such, Gotals number among the most sought-after hunters in the galaxy.
    [P]Gotal cones can detect another being's emotional state and intentions. Gotal
    horns are even sensitive enough to pick up such indistinct signals as neutrino
    emissions. Electronic devices can also be sensed by Gotals: in fact, most
    droids give off enough electromagnetic emissions to at least annoy a Gotal,
    and at worst to seriously disorient the horned beings. Consequently, the species
    is notoriously distrustful of droids. Gotals rely heavily on their cones,
    with their eyesight and hearing being quite weak, and their sense of smell almost
    completely absent.
    [P]At least some Gotals are able to sense the Force with their cones. Nevertheless,
    standard reference works such as the Catalog of Intelligent Life in the Galaxy are
    silent on the subject, and the writings of Mammon Hoole described this as a rumor
    which had "yet to be proven." Other sources indicate that both the Jedi Order
    and the Galactic Empire had conducted inconclusive research which attempted to train
    Gotals to sense the Force. The records of the Gotals themselves are split on the
    issue. Those sources which did describe Gotals sensing the Force varied in their
    descriptions. Some sources described it as an intense, overwhelming sensation,
    while others treated it as a mere "indistinct buzzing."
    [P]Gotals have flat, elongated faces with reddish, heavy-lidded eyes, small, flat
    noses, and a wide, downturned mouth full of blunt, yellow or white teeth. Their
    eyes vary in color, with individuals sporting shades of red, orange, yellow,
    gray, green, and black. Coarse, shaggy fur covers most of their bodies
    with the exception of the face, chest, and abdomen. Gotals are classified as
    mammals. Their overall body plan is humanoid, with proportions generally similar
    to Humans. Some Gotals have four fingers and a thumb with short, conical claws on
    each digit; others have only four or three digits per limb with much longer claws
    making up a large portion of each finger. Their skin color varies from
    gray-brown to black, and their fur came in white or shades of brown or gray.
    While male Gotals typically have a thick fringe of hair around their cheeks and chins,
    this is absent in female Gotals. Gotals shed their fur and most Gotals learn
    to control this process. Under extreme stress or nerves, however—as when surprised
    or frightened—Gotals can lose control of this process and begin shedding
    large clumps of fur. Gotals' natural body odor is similar to the smell of
    mildew and old sweat. Gotals are resistant to the venom produced by members of
    the Killik species.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
    Gotals form intense bonds with one another upon first meeting,[ and love at
    first "sight" is the norm among Gotals, whose empathic nature make the elaborate
    courtship rituals of other sentients unnecessary. Gotal will mate for life,
    and will bear young as soon as their lifestyles permitted it. Gotals only
    speak to each other to relay abstract information, since they have no need to
    vocally express their emotions (Ironically, since Gotals speak in a non-inflected
    monotone, they seemed emotionless to Humans and other non-Gotals.)
    [P]Young Gotals often have trouble assimilating the information arriving from
    their cones, and are in a constant state of agitated confusion until they learn
    to filter unwanted signals after about one standard year. Even then, it takes them
    until the age of twelve to attain emotional maturity, and they can sometimes be
    nearly psychotic until then. Despite this, Gotal parents are devoted to their
    children, and young Gotals will have children as soon as they can manage it.
    Mature Gotals are generally calm and peaceful individuals.
    [P]Gotal sensory cones allow them to keep their emotions to themselves. They
    tend to keep a calm and restrained demeanor when dealing with others, speaking
    of emotions only abstractly. This leads some non-Gotals to assume the species lacks
    emotion entirely, and many species are uncomfortable around and mistrustful
    of Gotals. Some feel that they are at a disadvantage when dealing with Gotals and
    their sensitive head cones, and other, more superstitious species, are wary of
    what they saw as the Gotals' supernatural powers. Nevertheless, the quirks of
    Gotals make them effective diplomats, mediators, businesspeople, and gamblers.
    Unless they sense evil intentions, Gotals were generally diplomatic and polite
    when interacting with members of other species.
    [P]Since their natural empathy make them instantly sensitive to the feelings of
    others, Gotals have little use for government or laws on their homeworld. This
    results in problems when dealing with non-Gotal societies. For example, no central
    authority figure can speak for Antar 4 as a whole in a crisis, and no organized
    Gotal military or police force can act on their behalf. The Gotal Foreign Affairs
    Commune do act as spokespeople for the Gotals
    during diplomatic crises, but their role in Gotal government is otherwise uncertain.
    Though they have little government of their own, Gotals do send representatives to
    participate in galactic-level governments, and Gotals living among non-Gotals
    even work in local government bureaucracies. Other species respect the Gotals
    for their discretion and restraint, but some individuals fear interacting with the
    horned beings for fear of having their emotional state revealed to others.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Antar 4 is the fourth of six moons orbiting the gas giant Antar and is homeworld 
    of the Gotal race. Located in the Inner Rim, the moon is situated in the Prindaar 
    system.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    The Gotals speak both Basic and Gotal, their native tongue. This language lacks
    vocabulary to express emotional states, and even their version of Basic avoids such
    terms and context. Some Gotals speak Basic with a bleating cadence. Non-Gotals
    are incapable of mastering Gotal because so much of the language relies on unspoken
    cues sensed with head cones.
  </Description>
  <Source Page="21">Fly Casual</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>3</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>1</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>9</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>8</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>PERC</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankAdd>0</RankAdd>
      <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
      <isCareer>false</isCareer>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>GOTALOC1</Key>
      <Name>Senses</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>GOTALOC1OP1</Key>
          <Name>Energy Sensitivity</Name>
          <Description>Once per encounter as a maneuver, may sense the presence and current emotional states of all living things within short range.</Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
