<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Species xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>GRAN</Key>
  <Name>Gran</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Gran[h4]
    The Gran are sentient mammalian humanoids native to the planet Kinyen, though they
    have colonies across the galaxy, including settlements on the planets Hok and Malastare.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    Gran can easily be identified by their three eyes and their goat-like snout.
    Female Gran also have three breasts. Gran are able to sense one another's
    emotions and disposition by noting subtle changes in body heat and skin color. The
    Gran have excellent vision, able to resolve more colors than most species, and even
    able to see into the infrared. Gran have two stomachs, having evolved from herbivorous
    grazing animals who lived in herds on the mountains and highlands of Kinyen,
    surviving on the local Goatgrass, for which Gran kept their taste. Gran chew
    and digest their food quite slowly, savoring the flavor carefully. A single
    meal can take almost an entire day to finish, but a Gran will often not need to
    eat for several days afterwards.
    [P]A recessive genetic mutation sometimes causes some Gran to suffer from misshapen
    extremities, with hands and feet swelling to abnormal sizes. While not affecting the
    individual's ability to do finer work, the handicap nonetheless often results in
    social isolation. Gran scientists intently study the trait to attempt to find a
    cure.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
    The peaceful nature of Gran society is a reflection of their homeworld, Kinyen.
    Kinyen boasts large and rolling grasslands and highlands, a dense and beautiful
    forest, and one of the longest and clearest rivers in the Sumitra sector.
    The beauty of this planet, and the need for primitive Gran to band together for
    defense against predatory animals, helped the Gran develop strong bonds of home
    and family in their society (once they became a civilized species, the Grans set
    aside fenced nature preserves for the carnivores which once threatened them).
    Grans also mate for life, forming such strong bonds that they generally die
    within days of a mate's death. It is rare for any Gran to leave his or her
    planet of origin once they have taken a mate.
    [P]The Grans are also very protective of their families, and are some of the most
    devoted parents in the galaxy. This is because of their very powerful and sensitive
    sight, which can sense the emotions of their mates and their children. Gran society
    maintains its balance by setting up strict career quotas, and making sure young Gran
    are educated for a specific job that best serves his or her talents. While other
    species who value freedom tend to criticize such a rigid social system, to the Gran
    it is both logical and essential. Gran religion revolves around the worship of
    the goddess Doellin.
    [P]Gran have a strong need for companionship—a Gran left alone for too long will go
    insane or die of loneliness. Generally, they need other Gran for companionship,
    but some Gran are able to form sufficiently strong bonds with aliens. The most feared
    punishment among the Gran is exile. Lone, outcast Gran, often wearing black to avoid
    painful memories of the colorful cities of their homeworld, are generally given a
    wide berth by experienced spacers. Grans isolated from Gran society are often
    unreliable, easily bribed, and easily addicted to drugs and liquors, though they are
    shrewd and often under-estimated. Conversely, Gran within their society are
    peaceful and amiable, with a keen sense of their place in society, and unselfish
    instincts putting the greater good ahead of their individual wants.
    [P]With such close bonds formed throughout the Gran community, it is unsurprising
    that they concentrated their cities into very small areas, so they are never out of
    touch with their many relatives. These cities, while hosting a majority of the
    population of Kinyen, also host the small government of the Gran. The government is
    a loose group of delegates from the major Gran families who usually controll different
    aspects of Gran society. One delegate is selected randomly every three and a half
    standard years to be the leader of this group. It is only due to the very peaceful
    sensibilities of the Gran race that this system works at all. Indeed, the
    only known major conflicts between Gran took place very early in Kinyen's history,
    before 10,000 BBY. Even these wars resulted from matters of survival, rather than
    strong emotional conflicts between the Gran or rival nations.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Kinyen is an agriworld in the Expansion Region, located on the Corellian Trade
    Spine. It is the Gran home world, with a recorded history dating back to 10,000 BBY.
    Though it was an outpost of the violent Rakata during the Pre-Republic era, during its
    recorded history, the planet has had no local wars.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    Gran is the language of the Grans from the planet Kinyen. It has also been exported to
    Gran colonies such as Malastare or Stend IV.
    [P]Many Grans learn to speak Basic. However, they also try to make their servants,
    such as the Dugs, learn Gran language.
  </Description>
  <Sources>
    <Source Page="56">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Source Page="22">Far Horizons</Source>
  </Sources>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>1</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>3</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>9</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>GRANCH1</Key>
      <Name>Skills</Name>
      <Description />
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>GRANCH1OP1</Key>
          <Name>One rank in Charm</Name>
          <Description>Gran may take one rank in Charm</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>CHARM</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
              <RankAdd>0</RankAdd>
              <RankLimit>0</RankLimit>
              <isCareer>false</isCareer>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
        <Option>
          <Key>GRANCH1OP2</Key>
          <Name>One rank in Negotiation</Name>
          <Description>Gran may take one rank in Negotiation</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>NEG</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
              <RankAdd>0</RankAdd>
              <RankLimit>0</RankLimit>
              <isCareer>false</isCareer>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>GRANCH2</Key>
      <Name>Vision</Name>
      <Description />
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>GRANCH2OP1</Key>
          <Name>Enhanced Vision</Name>
          <Description>When making ranged combat or Perception checks, Gran remove up to [SETBACK][SETBACK] imposed due to environmental conditions or concealment (but not defense).</Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
  <NoForceAbilities>false</NoForceAbilities>
</Species>