<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Species>
  <Key>GUNGAN</Key>
  <Name>Gungan</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Gungan[h4]
    The Gungans are sentient amphibious humanoids native to the planet of Naboo.
    Prior to the Invasion of Naboo, the Gungans were a largely isolationist society.
    They were able to combine machinery with biology. They lived in large bubble-like
    domes under water. Gungans have strong leg muscles for swimming, and are aided by
    their long fin-like ears. Their arms end in four-fingered hands, and their feet
    have three stubby toes each. Females tend to be slightly smaller, with sleeker
    faces. They often tie their long ears back.
    [P]The long Gungan face has a tough yet flexible bill for burrowing and rooting
    out food. They also have long muscular tongues with which they scooped mollusks
    and lesser amphibians from the Naboo swamps. Their teeth are large and blunt,
    capable of cracking through shellfish. Their large nostrils completely seal
    for underwater travel.
    [P]While most spacefarers would dismiss Gungans as primitives, they developed
    an advanced, albeit unique, technology. They grow the basic structures of buildings,
    vehicles and technology and adorn them with artistic flourishes and organic
    lines. This gives Gungan technology a very fluid, non-rectilinear look.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
    The Gungans are separated into two races: the lanky orange, yellow or
    red-skinned Otolla race, and the heavier green-skinned Ankura race.
    However, they all exhibit many of the same basic physical traits.
    Starting life as tadpoles, Gungans develop into tall beings with extremely
    flexible cartilaginous skeletons. Strong leg muscles allow for powerful and
    quick frog-kick style swimming through water as well as a remarkable jumping
    ability while on land. Fin-like ears (called haillu) also aid them in swimming,
    as well as expressing emotions like aggression, friendship, and fear. They have
    partially retractable eyestalks with nictitating membranes when underwater. Green
    eyes are unusual amongst Gungans.
    [P]Expressive faces and long bills with flaring nostrils are signatures of
    Gungan physiology. Lengthy muscular tongues and large blunt teeth allow them
    to eat lesser amphibians, while a layer of tough skin on the head allow for
    burrowing. A Gungan's arms end in four digits, and their feet have three stubby
    toes. Females are smaller with sleeker faces and tend to tie their ears back.
    Female with light-colored ear flaps are considered attractive by male Gungans,
    while the ones with dark-colored haillu are thought of as 'boyish'. As male
    Gungans aged, they develop prominent whiskers, resembling
    those of a catfish. Both sexes have a lifespan of 65 galactic standard years.
    [P]Gungans have nostrils that seal when they entered the water. They also boast
    very strong lungs, allowing them to both hold their breath for extended periods of
    time and to withstand the pressure of deep water, along with well-padded kneecaps
    and powerful calves and legs for increased swimming speed. However, because they
    are so well-adapted to their watery environment, their skin dries easily in hot
    and arid climates.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
    Utilizing their own unique phraseology, Gungans established a rather successful
    history of scholarly excellence, albeit unknown to the galaxy at large. Among their
    achievements include the epic poem Das Depu Epu Sea, or Deep Dark Water. This ode
    to Da Beauty Al'Round was a source of great pride to these noble beings.
    [P]Gungan alpha-males often exhibit a series of oral clicks when aggravated or
    angered. The Gungan military is made up of mostly male volunteers.
    [P]Gungans were basically a generous and peaceful people until the Trade Federation
    invaded. They loved to have visitors and warmly welcomed them; however, they would
    remain suspicious until the visitors had earned their respect.
    [P]Gungans are not tolerant of anyone who threatens their peaceful culture. They
    have very strict laws, and will go to the extremes to punish anyone who has committed
    a minor crime. Vandals, for example, could be given a sentence of exile, caning, or
    even stoning.
    [P]If a Gungan is cast out of society, it is very difficult for them to return.
    If they do manage to return legally, they will often be subjected to heavy
    discrimination. This can make life very difficult for them and can go on for
    months or years, until their past offenses disappear from memory. In addition,
    returning back to the settlement from which they were exiled illegally will sometimes result
    in the death penalty, especially if they bring along outsiders. It usually requires
    a significant deed to not only have their exile revoked, but also be welcomed back
    to the fold.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
    Naboo (pronounced /nə'bu/) is a planet that is the sector capital of the Chommell
    sector near the Outer Rim territories. It is a largely unspoiled world with large
    plains, swamps and seas
    [P]Naboo is a geologically unique world in the galaxy. A plasmic molten outer core
    surrounded an inner core, believed to be composed primarily of a nickel-iron alloy,
    with very small amounts of some other elements. These elements are found in abundance
    in other chemical compositions in the galaxy, but it is the unique properties of the
    plasma which interested astrophysicists, plasma which the two primary civilizations
    harnessed to supply clean and efficient energy highly valued throughout the galaxy.
    [P]The plasmic magma "seethes and bubbles" from the center of the planet carving l
    abyrinths of winding tunnels and caverns similar to lava tubes of traditional magma
    flows. Much of these abyssal labyrinths are submerged in great underground oceans,
    which are home to immense aquatic animals and creatures that are never seen on the
    surface. Animals such as the colo claw fish, opee sea killer, sando aqua monster and
    others inhabited this underworld realm. Gungans dominate these "underwaterways,"
    using them as a highway of sorts between their surface Holy Places and their underwater
    cities. The Gungans also use these tunnels for trading between Bubble cities.
    [P]Plasmic eruptions find their way to the porous crust of the planet, affecting
    geographic features there such as mountain chains and plate tectonics.
    [P]The surface of Naboo is covered by dense swamps, rolling grass plains, seas and
    verdant hills. The largest mountain chain, the Gallo Mountains, bisects the largest
    continent and divides the great grass plains of the north from the Lianorm Swamp and
    bayous in the south. South of the Lianorm Swamp is the great Paonga Sea, where at
    the bottom lay the Gungan city of Otoh Gunga. The Lake Country is an area known for
    its natural beauty, and is home to many vacation estates.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
    Gungan Basic, also called Gunganese, is the language spoken by the Gungans of the 
    planet Naboo. It is a language mostly derived from Naboo settlers' language, Basic, 
    spoken in an accent. Occasionally, a word from Old Gungan will appear in dialogue, a 
    term usually without any obvious meaning unless translated.
    [P]Humans can usually understand it and, similarly, Gungans can understand Humans 
    speaking Basic (even in written form). Most one-syllable words pertaining to the self 
    will contain a suffix of -sa, for example, "We-sa" and "You-sa". Many one-syllable 
    words ending in a consonant will end with -u.
  </Description>
  <Source Page="101">Nexus of Power</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>1</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>3</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>ATHL</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>GUNGAB1</Key>
      <Name>Underwater</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>GUNGAB1OP1</Key>
          <Name>Amphibious</Name>
          <Description>Gungans may breathe underwater without penalty and never suffer movement penalties for traveling through water.</Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
  <!--<SubSpeciesList>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>GUNGSUB1</Key>
      <Name>Otolla</Name>
      <Description>
        The Otolla subspecies has long ears and eyes on extendable and
        retractable stalks.  Otolla skin is either
        orange or purple in hue.
      </Description>
    </SubSpecies>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>GUNGSUB2</Key>
      <Name>Ankura</Name>
      <Description>
        The Ankuras have hooded eyes, broad wide heads, and green skin.
        Like the Otolla, they also have long ears, which are sometimes tied together
        behind the head.
      </Description>
    </SubSpecies>
  </SubSpeciesList>-->
</Species>
