<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Species xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>KLATOO</Key>
  <Name>Klatooinian</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Klatooinian[h4]

Klatooinians are a humanoid species from the planet Klatooine, located in the Si'Klaata Cluster. For most of their history, they were closely associated with the Hutts, as criminal henchmen, soldiers, and slaves. By the time of the Galactic Civil War, however, some Klatooinians began to break away from their servitude.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
The Klatooinians are tall, humanoid beings. Their skin is rough, with color ranging from olive green to dark brown. They have a flat nose and a canine muzzle, with dark eyes under their thick heavy brows. The severe desert climate of their homeworld has made their species strong and enduring. To survive in their hostile world was a mark of great physical and mental strength. That is why the Klatoonians respect and admire the elderly and experienced of their kind.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
The Klatooinians are a proud people and are traditionalists, used to following the traditions laid by their ancestors. They also have a strong religious upbringing, that can tie them down, as a species or a clan, to another entity, be it a Hutt or a crime syndicate. When a Klatooinian makes a vow, you can rest assured that he will do anything in his power to complete their vow. But you can also be assured that if a Klatooinian ever vowed to kill you, you will be hunted till the Klatooinian or you had been killed. Thus is the way of their species.
[P]This religious steadfast pride and loyalty, coupled with their strong statures, has made the Klatooinians ideal for guard duty, since anyone with an ounce of intelligence would think twice about trying to rush a Klatooinian. They have been a favorite to crime syndicates and Hutts for their steadfast loyalty, and you would never have to think twice about them if they made a vow.

[P]Klatooinian civilization is notable for its strong belief in tradition and the wisdom of elders. The center of their culture is the Fountain of Ancients, a slowly evolving natural glass sculpture on Klatooine's Derelkoos Desert. Long before the formation of the Galactic Republic, primitive Klatooinians discovered the Fountain, and revered it as a symbol of patience, tenacity, and the idea of strength coming from age. 
[P]Their society is ruled by a Council of Elders, which grants young Klatooinians few rights. Klatooinians are taught the myths and traditions of their people from a young age, in a process which tended to suppress individuality. At the age of ten, they would be sold into servitude, with the most rebellious youths sent into the harshest conditions. 
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
Klatooine is a desert planet, located within the Si'Klaata Cluster, and the homeworld of the Klatooinian race, found deep in Hutt Space.
[P]The Klatooinian is a race native to Klatooine, indentured to the Hutts since before the rise of the Old Republic. Along with the Vodran and Nikto races, the Klatooinians have served the Hutts since the battles against Xim the Despot. They are a tall, humanoid race with flat, canine faces and coarse skin. The Klatooinian culture is strongly tied to traditional values, and has been as patient and tenacious as the Fountain of Ancients. They also, like the Fountain, strove to grow stronger with age. The Klatooinians have often referred to themselves as the Children of the Fountain, since they have developed many of the Fountain's characteristics. At the age of ten, every Klatooinan is sold into servitude, usually to local governments. Especially troublesome youths are sold into slavery. This helps the young Klatooinans learn to respect and admire their elders and the traditions of their people. However, they have forever been under the oppression of the Hutts. Like the Fountain of the Ancients, the Klatooinans hope that they can endure long enough to grow strong with age and shed the Hutt yolk.
[P]The Fountain of the Ancients is a unique natural phenomenon located in the center of the Derelkoos Desert. In a bowl-shaped depression, liquid wintrium seeps from the desert sand and begins to crystallize. As it solidifies over several millenia, the wintrium forms wonderful shapes and patterns, continually expanding and growing. Because of its hardness, the Fountain's shape can be altered only by powerful weaponry, and has stood untouched for as long as the Klatooinian race can remember. The Fountain's continually growth, increasing strength, and tenacity have instilled similar values in the Klatooinian people. It also has certain religious connotations to them. Wintrium this glass-like substance remains in liquid form at very low temperatures, and can take as much as 10,000 years to solidify under normal conditions. It is found in the Derelkoos Desert of Klatooine, where it seeps from the desert and creates incredibly beautiful, natural sculptures. The Klatooinans call the landmark the Fountain of the Ancients, and revere it for its tenacious and wonderful existence.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
The Klatooinian language was once the native language of the Klatooinians, the native people of Klatooine. By the latter days of the Galactic Republic, it was a dead language.  Klatooinians now speak Huttese, the language of the Hutt.</Description>
  <Source Page="20">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>3</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>1</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>KLATOC1</Key>
      <Name>Skill</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>KLATOC1OP1</Key>
          <Name>Additional Non-Career Skill</Name>
          <Description>
            Klatooninians start the game with one additional rank of one non career skill of his choice.
          </Description>
          <StartingSkillTraining>
            <SkillTraining>
              <SkillCount>1</SkillCount>
              <Requirement>
                <NonCareer>true</NonCareer>
              </Requirement>
            </SkillTraining>
          </StartingSkillTraining>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>KLATOC2</Key>
      <Name>Skills</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>KLATOC2OP1</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Brawl</Name>
          <Description>Klatooninians may begin the game with one rank in Brawl.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>BRAWL</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
        <Option>
          <Key>KLATOC2OP2</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Ranged-Heavy</Name>
          <Description>Klatooninians may begin the game with one rank in Ranged-Heavy.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>RANGHVY</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
        <Option>
          <Key>KLATOC2OP3</Key>
          <Name>One Rank in Ranged-Light</Name>
          <Description>Klatooninians may begin the game with one rank in Ranged-Light.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>RANGLT</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>