<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Species>
  <Key>KUBAZ</Key>
  <Name>Kubaz</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Kubaz[h4]

The Kubaz or Kubazian are an insectivorous species native to the planet Kubindi in the Outer Rim Territories. Although relatively new to the Galactic community at the time of the institution of the Galactic Empire, the species was already ubiquitous throughout the Republic during the Great Galactic War and the Clone Wars.
    [P][B]Physiology:[b]
A bipedal humanoid species of mammalian sentients, the Kubaz are distinctive for their short, prehensile facial snouts which are used for reaching insects within their hives. Having adapted to their sun-scorched, vegetation-deprived world, the Kubaz learned to survive off their world's native insect population. Filled with two rows of teeth for gnashing their food, the Kubaz trunk also functions as a highly sensitive nose. Green-black skinned, Kubaz have short bristly hair growing from their heads and they stand upon two-toed feet. Having evolved on their homeworld of Kubindi, a planet which orbited a blue star, the Kubaz are highly sensitive to red wavelengths. When traveling to planets with a red or yellow star, the Kubaz are forced to don protective eye wear to avoid damaging their sensitive eyes.
    [P][B]Society:[b]
The Kubazi society is based on a clan structure which dwells in underground nests. Ruled by a queen, each clan takes the name of the queen they are descended from. Developing a non-verbal language of hand gestures which indicated their intentions, Kubaz are able to speak Galactic Basic Standard, though with a strong nasally accent. When interacting with other species, some Kubaz will share certain hand signals with non-Kubaz in order to ease communications. Touching the nose, head, or shoulders can indicate intent, direction, and number. Obsessed with tact and decorum, the Kubaz place a high emphasis on the family unit and proper courtesies, displaying truthfulness to a fault. Valuing art and literature with such vigor as to sometimes practice smuggling of great works, the Kubaz do not find such pursuits to be wrong or unlawful.
[P]Due to their habitual diet on Kubindi, the Kubaz have poor relations with other sentient insectile species such as the Geonosians.
    [P][B]Homeworld:[b]
Kubindi is a terrestrial world and home to the Kubaz. A planet that orbits a blue giant star that emits powerful solar flares, Kubindi is regularly hit with this radiation, causing erratic weather patterns and making the world dry and arid.
    [P][B]Language:[b]
Kubazian, or Kubazi, is the native language of the Kubaz species from Kubindi. Most Kubaz are fluent in both Kubazi and Basic, although only literate in their own language.
[P]Kubazi language is very nasal, and Kubaz usually have a high-pitched accent when speaking other languages, such as Basic. The Kubaz, however, learn new languages quickly.  </Description>
  <Source>Unofficial Species Menagerie</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>1</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>3</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>9</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>11</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>PERC</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
    <TalentModifier>
      <Key>STRSMART</Key>
      <RankAdd>1</RankAdd>
    </TalentModifier>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices />
</Species>