<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Species>
  <Key>SQUIB</Key>
  <Name>Squib</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Squib[h4]
Squibs are a sentient species from Skor II known for collecting, trading, and haggling. Adult Squibs have humanoid bodies that average a meter in height. They are covered in colorful fur and have pointed snouts, tufted ears, and large eyes. Squibs taste objects by rubbing them over their fur. They are gregarious, insatiably curious, and obsessed with haggling and deal-making. It is said that the easiest way to get information from a Squib is to propose a trade.
[P][B]Physiology:[b]
Squibs are small, sentient, humanoid mammals with both rodent and canine characteristics. They range from 0.8 to 1.2 meters in height[11] and weigh twenty-two kilograms on average. Their pink skin is covered in fur that range from white, gray, black, and brown to blue, violet, and red. The coat offers some protection from cold weather, but, more importantly, it serve as an olfactory organ, able to pick up scents at a distance and ascertain intrinsic details—such as penetrating through a disguise or identifying a forgery—when rubbed against. The species has both male and female sexes, although non-Squibs often have difficulty determining the sex of a Squib based on his or her appearance alone.
[P]Squib eyes are large in relation to the skull and located on the sides of the head. They come in shades of blue, yellow, red, and brown. Their large ears often sport tufts of fur whose color can differ from that of the main coat; the ears point upward and can pivot to zero in on specific sounds. The short Squib muzzle tapersd to a bewhiskered black nose. Their mouths are full of forbidding, sharp, white teeth, and their flexible cheeks are capable of storing items. The species has nimble, five-fingered hands and five toes on each foot. Non-Squibs often consider the small beings humorous or cute in appearance.
[P]The Squibs have quick metabolisms and relatively short life spans. A Squib is considered a child—referred to as a fuzzling—until nine standard years of age. As he or she matures, the fur changes color, a phenomenon that causes a dappled appearance on the back; similarly, the eyes and ears grow more quickly than the rest of the body, causing the latter to flop until the rest of the fuzzling's body grows enough to catch up. Sexual maturity occurs at thirteen standard years. Beginning at around thirty-nine years, a Squib enters middle age, when the fur grays and the face wrinkles. Squib life expectancy is about sixty-five standard years.
[P][B]Society:[b]
Squibs are cheerful, gregarious, and overconfident to the point of egotism. Their biology leads to a common Squib greeting: rubbing a person's palm across the cheek fur. As Squibs often wear gloves, the gesture conveys more information than a simple handshake. They are friendly and non-threatening, making them quite likable—at first. Over time, Squib acquaintances can grow to regard the beings as slightly annoying to downright obnoxious Furbag and furball are derisive terms for Squibs.
[P]Squibs are inherently curious. They handle anything that interested them, usually by rubbing it against their fur with little forethought as to whether doing so might be harmful. Squib curiosity and propensity for haggling make them unabashed pack rats. Although the species has no need for clothing to protect themselves from the elements, they wear clothes and footwear for reasons of appearance and extra storage; typical clothing includes pockets and pouches to stuff with odds and ends that catch their eye, since a Squib can never tell when a particular item might be useful in making a deal. Still, individuals leave fur exposed to facilitate olfaction. Their accumulative drives earn the species a reputation as thieves among some members of the galactic community.
[P][B]Homeworld:[b]
Skor II is a planet in the Squab system and the homeworld of the Squibs. It is located in the Outer Rim Territories just west of the Rimma Trade Route. The world is small, with a varied terrain and climate that provide it with vast natural resources. The planet's system of government, known as the polyanarchy, is headed by a king. One major population center is Metrobig City, site of the Metrobig Interplanetary Blastport.
[P][B]Language:[b]
Squibbian is the native language of the Squib species from Skor II.
[P]Most Squibs know both Squibbian and Basic, although they are only literate in their own language. However, they only manage to get a limited grasp on Basic. As a result, a Squib seems inarticulate when speaking Basic. Their sentences in Squib have surface and deeper meanings, and at least one of these (usually the surface meaning) is lost when translated to Basic, except for another Squib.</Description>
  <Source>Unofficial Species Menagerie</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>1</Brawn>
    <Agility>3</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>9</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>11</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>NEG</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankAdd>0</RankAdd>
      <RankLimit>0</RankLimit>
      <isCareer>false</isCareer>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers />
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>SQUIBCH1</Key>
      <Name>Skill</Name>
      <Description />
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>SQUIBCH1OP1</Key>
          <Name>Mechanics</Name>
          <Description>Squibs always treat Mechanics as
being a career skill, regardless of their starting
career.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>MECH</Key>
              <RankStart>0</RankStart>
              <RankAdd>0</RankAdd>
              <RankLimit>0</RankLimit>
              <isCareer>true</isCareer>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
          <TalentModifiers />
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>SQUIBCH2</Key>
      <Name>Size</Name>
      <Description />
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>SQUIBCH2OP1</Key>
          <Name>Reduced Silhouette</Name>
          <Description>Squibs have a Silhouette of 0.</Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
  <WeaponModifiers />
</Species>