<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Species>
  <Key>ZELTRON</Key>
  <Name>Zeltron</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Zeltron[h4]
Zeltrons are a near-Human species, made physically distinctive by their skin and hair, which comes in different shades of red ranging from pink to deep red to black. Most of them are considered highly attractive by Human, near-Human, and even some non-humanoid standards. They are also known for being extremely gullible.
[P][B]Physiology:[b]
Zeltrons are one of the few near-Human races who have differentiated from the baseline stock enough to be considered a new species of the Human genus, rather than simply a subspecies. They possess two biological traits of note. The first is that they all produce potent pheromones, similar to the Falleen species, which enhance their attractiveness and likeability. The second is a limited telepathic ability, used to project emotions onto others, as well as allowing them to read and even feel the emotions of others. Because of their telepathic ability, positive emotions such as happiness, love and pleasure become very important to them, while negative ones such as anger, fear, or depression are shunned.
[P]Another difference between Zeltrons and Humans is the presence of a second liver, which allowed Zeltrons to enjoy a larger number of alcoholic beverages than other humanoids.
[P]It is said that Zeltrons tend to look familiar to other people, even if they have never met them. Most Zeltrons are in excellent physical shape, and their incredible metabolisms allow them to eat even the richest of foods.
[P][B]Society:[b]
Zeltron culture is highly influenced by sexuality and the pursuit of pleasure in general. Most of their art and literature is devoted to the subject, producing some of the raciest pieces in the galaxy. They look upon monogamy as a quaint, but impractical, practice. They are also very gifted with holograms, and are the creators of Hologram Fun World. Their Elixir of Infatuation is notorious for its powerful amorous effects.
[P]Zeltrons are known to dress in wildly colorful or revealing attire. It is common to see Zeltrons wearing shockingly bright shades of neon colors in wildly designed bikinis, or nearly skin tight clothing of other sorts with bizarre color designs, patterns, and symbols.
[P]Zeltrons are often stereotyped as lazy thrill-seekers, owing to their hedonistic pursuits. Indeed, their homeworld of Zeltros thrives as a luxury world and "party planet," as much for their own good as for others. If anyone isn't having a good time on Zeltros, the Zeltrons will certainly know of it, and will do their best to correct it. Though their first inclination is to love; if pushed to do so, Zeltrons can prove to be formidable warriors.
[P][B]Homeworld:[b]
Zeltros is a planet in the Inner Rim, and the homeworld of the Zeltron race. An opulent world, hedonism is the doctrine encouraged by the empathetic Zeltrons, and Zeltros is continuously in a state of never ending revelry. The Zeltron appreciation of beauty in its many forms leads to luxurious art and architecture covering the world, and the galaxy's most wealthy favored Zeltros as a vacation destination. Many who come to the planet are taken in by the celebratory atmosphere and the powerful pheromones of the Zeltron people to the point they find it difficult to leave, and even planetary invasions often flounder in the face of Zeltros' planet-wide festivities.
[P][B]Language:[b]
Galactic Basic Standard (or Galactic Basic, Galactic Standard, Galaxy Standard or just Basic) is the most prevalent and most used language in the galaxy and is spoken by the Zeltron.</Description>
  <Source>Unofficial Species Menagerie</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>1</Willpower>
    <Presence>3</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>90</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>CHARM</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankAdd>0</RankAdd>
      <RankLimit>0</RankLimit>
      <isCareer>false</isCareer>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers />
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>ZELTRONCH1</Key>
      <Name>Empathy</Name>
      <Description />
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>ZELTRONCH1OP1</Key>
          <Name>Empathy</Name>
          <Description>Add [SETBACK] to all incoming Charm or Deception rolls that target the Zeltron.</Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>ZELTRONCH2</Key>
      <Name>Pheromones</Name>
      <Description />
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>ZELTRONCH2OP1</Key>
          <Name>Pheromones</Name>
          <Description>Zeltrons add [ADVANTAGE] to all Charm, Deception, and Negotiation skill checks.</Description>
          <DieModifiers>
            <DieModifier>
              <SkillKey>CHARM</SkillKey>
              <AdvantageCount>1</AdvantageCount>
            </DieModifier>
            <DieModifier>
              <SkillKey>DECEP</SkillKey>
              <AdvantageCount>1</AdvantageCount>
            </DieModifier>
            <DieModifier>
              <SkillKey>NEG</SkillKey>
              <AdvantageCount>1</AdvantageCount>
            </DieModifier>
          </DieModifiers>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
  <WeaponModifiers />
</Species>