<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Species xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>ZYGERRIAN</Key>
  <Name>Zygerrian</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Zygerrian[h4]
The Zygerrians are a sentient species of Near-Humans native of the planet Zygerria. Members of the species are medium-sized, standing 1.7 meters tall on average and weighing around sixty kilograms. The Zygerrians are distinguished by a number of bony spurs on their face. The species is well-known for its long history of violence, war, and slavery, which they view as a natural order of life. This contributes to the fact that the Zygerrians are feared across the galaxy. The founders of the Zygerrian Slavers Guild, the Zygerrians conducted slaving operations in the Outer Rim Territories for centuries before the Clone Wars. At one point, the species was crushed by the Jedi Order, but they eventually recovered.
[P][B]Physiology:[b]
The Zygerrians are a bipedal sentient species, biologically related to baseline Humans. Feline in appearance, the species possesses strong, angular features, with long fangs jutting from their jaws. The Zygerrians' faces and ears are almost entirely covered with fur, which ranged in color from brown to gray or red. Males traditionally have more hair than females, with straps of fur growing on their cheeks. Male Zygerrians also display a number of bony spurs protruding from the chin. Females lacked the chin spurs, but they instead have smaller protrusions on their forehead.

[P]With an average lifespan of eighty-one years, the Zygerrians reach adolescence at ten years, are considered adult at seventeen, middle-aged at forty, and old at sixty-one. Medium-sized, they usually grow up to 1.7 meters and weigh around sixty kilograms. They generally have sallow complexions and are physically strong, but some individuals suffer from obesity.
[P][B]Society:[b]
A warlike species, the Zygerrians hold strength—both physical and mental—in great esteem, viewing it as a means to gain power and authority. They believe that it is the natural order of life for the strong to dominate the weak, so slavery is normal for the species, and a display of weakness can mean death or enslavement in their culture. Because of this, the species willingly cultivates an image as dangerous and unpredictable to discourage others from challenging them. This tactic works, and the Zygerrians are feared in spaceports across the galaxy, earning fame for their history of violence, piracy, slavery, and war. Despite all of that, they are still considered an advanced civilization. The species' natural physical strength is well-complemented by their mastery of various weapons, such as retractable shock whips. The Zygerrians utilize various creatures to travel on their homeworld, including the winged brezak creatures, which the Zygerrian royal guard use to patrol the ground for escaped slaves. In order to transfer slaves between planets, the species uses highly durable freighters. Each transport containes space for numerous enslaved individuals, yet only require one pilot to operate it. The Zygerrians are cunning, ensuring that they have the upper hand in any situation. They traditionally settle their differences with an unarmed fistfight.
[P]The Zygerrian people are organized into clans and classes. They have a noble class, many members of which, despite their high status, pursue a career in the military. The Zygerrian Head of State is a monarch; female rulers hold the title of Queen. The center of the Zygerrian society, however, is the Zygerrian Slavers Guild that focuses on slave trade in the Outer Rim Territories. Founded centuries before the Clone Wars, the organization thrived in their territory, mostly due to its well-organized nature and the Galactic Republic's diffuse presence in the Outer Rim. Each Zygerrian slaver has to pay a yearly membership fee to join the Guild and is then allocated a patch of space in which to work. The size of that patch varies from one planet to an entire system, depending on the amount of money the slaver paid as his fee. Compared to other slaver organizations, the Zygerrians are considered "honorable" by the Twi'leks, who prefer them as slave masters, since the Zygerrians' approach to slaving reduced the damage it did to the Twi'lek society.
[P][B]Homeworld:[b]
Zygerria isthe homeworld of the near-Human Zygerrian species.  The planet experienced success during the thousands of years the Zygerrians maintained their slave labor industry, but after the Jedi cracked down on the slaving operations, it faded from glory. Slavery was brought up again when the Zygerrians collaborated with the Separatists during the Clone Wars.

[P]During the Zygerrian Slave Empire's height, the population had fortresses and cities built on top of the mesas scattered throughout the planet, using slave labor. After the empire's collapse, these buildings remained impressive sights to tourists, bringing visitors even from Alderaan.

[P]Aside from being a major slavery world, it hosts several podraces annually, which attracted large numbers of spectators.
[P][B]Language:[b]
Zygerrian primarily speak Galactic Basic Standard.</Description>
  <Source>Unofficial Species Menagerie</Source>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>1</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>3</Presence>
    <Requirement>
      <WearingArmor>false</WearingArmor>
      <Career>false</Career>
      <Specialization>false</Specialization>
      <NonCareer>false</NonCareer>
      <SoakAtLeast>0</SoakAtLeast>
    </Requirement>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>11</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <DefenseRanged>0</DefenseRanged>
    <DefenseMelee>0</DefenseMelee>
    <SoakValue>0</SoakValue>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
    <ForceRating>0</ForceRating>
    <Requirement>
      <WearingArmor>false</WearingArmor>
      <Career>false</Career>
      <Specialization>false</Specialization>
      <NonCareer>false</NonCareer>
      <SoakAtLeast>0</SoakAtLeast>
    </Requirement>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>COERC</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankAdd>0</RankAdd>
      <RankLimit>0</RankLimit>
      <isCareer>false</isCareer>
      <Requirement>
        <WearingArmor>false</WearingArmor>
        <Career>false</Career>
        <Specialization>false</Specialization>
        <NonCareer>false</NonCareer>
        <SoakAtLeast>0</SoakAtLeast>
      </Requirement>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
    <TalentModifier>
      <Key>FRENZ</Key>
      <RankStart>0</RankStart>
      <RankAdd>1</RankAdd>
      <RankLimit>0</RankLimit>
      <Requirement>
        <WearingArmor>false</WearingArmor>
        <Career>false</Career>
        <Specialization>false</Specialization>
        <NonCareer>false</NonCareer>
        <SoakAtLeast>0</SoakAtLeast>
      </Requirement>
    </TalentModifier>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices />
  <WeaponModifiers />
  <NoForceAbilities>false</NoForceAbilities>
</Species>